[
  {
    "question": "Where can I see my account balance?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your screen Trading balance is shown at on the card at the top of the page Click on Trading balance card to view more details about the funds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my Available Margin to Trade?",
    "answer": "Available Margin to Trade consists of your Funds balance & margin against eligible holdings."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to increase my Available Margin to Trade?",
    "answer": "You can increase your Available Margin to Trade by adding Funds or by creating a Margin Pledge against your eligible holdings in Accounts -> Stock Pledging."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Peak Margin requirement?",
    "answer": "Peak Margin is the minimum margin that must be collected by brokers from their clients in advance of placing any intraday / delivery order."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Peak Margin Shortfall?",
    "answer": "Peak Margin shortfall occurs when you buy a share from 80% margin released against delivery sell transactions and such sell position is subsequently bought back. You will be charged a penalty if margin shortfall is due to insufficient margin."
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to know how much cash is mine and how much is on margin?",
    "answer": "You can check your available cash and margin by visiting Account → Trading balance screen on web or mobile app. Here you will see the Cash balance and the margins from pledge holdings"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Margin Calculator & what is its use?",
    "answer": "Margin means the amount required to buy a specific stock/Index & differ from Index to Index or share to share. Margin calculator helps you to know the required Margin for a strategy that you wish to take."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I need to verify my mobile number?",
    "answer": "Verifying your mobile number helps us create a secure account for you, ensuring a smooth app experience and the safety of your account."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I continue if the mobile number linked to my bank is different from the one registered with the app?",
    "answer": "No, your details, including your mobile number, must match those verified by our banking partner. A mismatch will result in your application being rejected by the bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are permissions to send SMS and access phone state required?",
    "answer": "These permissions are needed to verify your mobile number by sending an SMS. Rest assured, these permissions are used solely for verification purposes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I link any SIM for FD purchase if I have a dual SIM phone?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can. However, we recommend using the SIM registered with your bank account for authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I retry the registration if it was not successful earlier?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can retry. Ensure you use the SIM linked to your bank account for authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I invest in FD if I do not have a PAN?",
    "answer": "No, currently, we only process fixed deposit requests for individuals with an active PAN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my PAN not getting verified?",
    "answer": "For booking fixed deposits, we need to verify your PAN with the regulated authorities. If there is a mismatch, the booking cannot be completed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if the name shown against my PAN is incorrect and I can't update it?",
    "answer": "The name linked to your PAN should be accurate for successful identity verification and KYC purposes. Please update your name to match your PAN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my Aadhar required?",
    "answer": "Aadhar is mandatory for identification and KYC setup for your account, necessary for processing your FD request."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I need a physical copy of my Aadhar?",
    "answer": "No, a physical copy is not required. We use secure platforms like DigiLocker and CKYC for verifying your Aadhar and other documents."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is DigiLocker?",
    "answer": "DigiLocker is a government initiative under the Digital India project for storing and verifying documents like PAN card, driving license, Aadhar card, school marksheets, and insurance papers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if there's a name mismatch and I can't complete the step?",
    "answer": "For successful FD booking, the name on your Aadhar and PAN should match. Correct the details on either your PAN or Aadhar card and retry."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I add a new address as my current address?",
    "answer": "Use the “add” button on the address choice screen to add an address that is not listed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I can't change my permanent address?",
    "answer": "The address from your Aadhar is considered your permanent address. You may add or select your current address to proceed with the FD application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can my permanent address be the same as my current address?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can select your permanent address as your current address if they are the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is video KYC required?",
    "answer": "Video KYC is required to complete the KYC verification step as mandated by the RBI."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if I am not available during bank working hours?",
    "answer": "If you have made the payment, we will notify you when the bank officers are available. If video KYC is not completed within 3 days, your money will be refunded to your bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I complete the Video KYC?",
    "answer": "Video KYC is available from Monday to Saturday, 09:00 AM to 08:00 PM. We will notify you to complete the video KYC during these hours if pending."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if video KYC fails?",
    "answer": "You can retry during banking hours within 2 days of FD booking if your video KYC fails."
  },
  {
    "question": "How will I know the status of my video KYC?",
    "answer": "Your video KYC details are verified by bank officers, which may take up to 3 hours. Track the video KYC and FD confirmation status on the ‘My Investments’ tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I can't move to the next step and complete my KYC verification?",
    "answer": "Retry using the correct details. If it still doesn’t work, try again later. If the issue persists, raise a ticket with our support team for assistance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are details related to occupation, income, and family required for FD booking?",
    "answer": "These details are required by the bank to create your fixed deposit and ensure communication if needed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my money deducted before video KYC?",
    "answer": "Your money is deducted before video KYC as it is the last step to verify your identity and book your FD. Your money is safe with the bank, and interest starts accumulating from the time of payment. In case of issues with VKYC, your money will be refunded within 7 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is required for completing a video KYC?",
    "answer": "Keep your PAN Card and a blank paper with a pen ready for the VKYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the NAV for my order?",
    "answer": "Applicable NAV is based on realization of fund by respective AMC house and subject to successful order processing by BSE star before cut-offs. Here ‘realization of funds’ means that NAV applicable for your order will depend on if the fund house has receievd money or not Please find the cut-off timings for various types of funds and orders Furthermore, NAV applicability for orders placed on Saturday, Sundays and other market/public holidays depends on when orders are placed on exchange. Here it is the next business day. Payments made via UPI mode generally result in same-day NAV if the order is placed before cut-off. This happens because settlement to ICCL happens generally happens before cut-off if made via UPI. Angel One depends on payment aggregator for ICCL settlements. Payments made via Netbanking generally result in next working day’s NAV. This happens as settlement to ICCL does not happen real time and generally takes places on ‘T+1’ basis. Angel One depends on payment aggregator for ICCL settlements. So even if order and payment is successful before cut-off, If the payment mode is netbanking, This might result in next day’s NAV. In Summary, In some cases, Even if order and payment happens before cut-off, NAV will depend on settlement to ICCL and realization of funds by AMC"
  },
  {
    "question": "I am not able to view my SIP order that I placed recently?",
    "answer": "Your orders will appear in orders only if you have made the payment today. If you have not selected ‘Make first payment now’. Your SIPs will appear only in SIPS section To view all your registered SIPs click please go to SIPs section or click on the link below: Manage SIPs"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my investment appear in my portfolio?",
    "answer": "Your Investments will appear in your ‘investments Tab’ when your orders moves to ‘Completed’ section of your Orders Tab. This happens when we get th e confirmation of Unit allotment by respective AMCs. This process generally takes 3/4 working days from order placement date. Your portfolio updation date in Order timeline is our estimate of when Unit allotment confirmation from AMC will come through. Please do not worry, This date date does not have any relation to your NAV date. Your NAV date depend on realization of funds by AMC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my instalment order in progress if SIP date is yet to come?",
    "answer": "We generally create your SIP installment order 2/3 working days before your due date as we have to co-ordinate with your Auto-pay linked bank account well in advance to ensure your SIP instalments goes through smoothly on due date. Order Date is when we create your SIP instalment order in our system and SIP due date is when money will be debited from your Autopay linked bank account. NAV applicable is usually of your SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will SIP amount get debited from my bank account for my Active SIPs?",
    "answer": "Your money will get debited automatically only if your SIP is linked to an autopay. If your SIP is linked to an autopay. SIP amount will get debited on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my order get successful?",
    "answer": "We have not received confirmation of successful payment from your bank. We will update the status as soon as possible. Your order will be confirmed when we receive confirmation of payment and confirmation of order placement by exchange. If both this stages are completed successfully. Your order will be successful. Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will happen if I do not have sufficient balance in my bank account on SIP due date?",
    "answer": "Your SIP instalment will fail if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your autopay linked bank account. Your bank can also charge you if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your bank account on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Money got deducted from my bank account but payment status shows payment in progress?",
    "answer": "We have not received confirmation of successful payment from your bank account. We will update the status as soon as possible. Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will refund happen if money has been debited but order has failed?",
    "answer": "Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "My money got debited but transaction shows as failed. When will refund happen?",
    "answer": "Please don’t worry, If we do not get payment confirmation or if payment/ order fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my SIP get created if my order is in Failed state?",
    "answer": "No, Your SIP will only be created when we received confirmation of successful payment from your bank account. If payment fails, Your SIP payment will not be registered."
  },
  {
    "question": "I got less money than what I placed an withdrawal order for?",
    "answer": "Your withdraw amount is converted to corresponding units while placing order at exchange. We calculate the units to be withdrawn based on current NAVs. Mutual fund NAVs (Net Asset Value) are updated every day after the market closes from Monday to Friday (All working days) For example, on June 3rd, you will see the NAV for June 2nd. Consider the following scenario for withdraw order placed on June 3rd: If NAV on 3rd June > 2nd June, You will receive an amount greater than order amount. If NAV on 3rd June < 2nd June, You will receive an amount lesser than order amount. In Summary, you will receive an amount according to latest NAV."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my next instalment be auto-debited?",
    "answer": "Your next SIP instalment will be Auto-Debited from your bank account if you have a valid Auto-pay setup. If not please setup an Autopay so that your future SIP instalments can be automated. To setup an Autopay, Please click below: {Setup Autopay}"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Stamp duty?",
    "answer": "The government collects 0.005% of the overall purchase amount of any mutual fund scheme as stamp duty. So even if entire amount is debited from your bank account, 0.005 percent of total amount is deducted and hence when order is completed, Same is reflected as invested amount."
  },
  {
    "question": "When I am trying to exit my position or place a Stop-Loss order, why is it being rejected?",
    "answer": "It may happen if you have a pending Stop-Loss (SL) or an exit order already. With an already pending stop-loss or exit order, you will need extra funds to be able to place a duplicate SL/exit order. If you do not have this extra fund in your account, then your duplicate exit order will get rejected. That’s why we inform you while exiting if there’s a Pending SL/exit order against a position, to avoid any duplicate orders and rejections."
  },
  {
    "question": "My Stop-Loss (SL) order was triggered but it did not get executed. Why did this happen?",
    "answer": "There could be 2 major reasons behind this: The asset may be lacking a buyer/seller at the defined stop-loss limit price due to a lack of market depth. Orders are queued while they are being purchased or sold. a. For example: Let’s say there are 50 buyers and 100 sellers who are waiting to trade on a scrip at ₹90. Upon reaching ₹90, the first 50 sellers’ orders will be executed, and the remaining 50 sellers will have to wait for new buyers. In case you are one of those remaining 50 sellers, your sell order will remain pending if there are no corresponding buyers and vice versa. The price movement during high volatility does not fulfill certain criteria e.g. suppose you have placed a sell stop-loss with trigger Price at ₹100 and limit price at ₹100. Now imagine that the LTP touched ₹100 (here, the SL would be triggered) and quickly went below ₹100 due to high volatility. The limit price of ₹100 means the stop-loss order would get executed at only ₹100 or more. Now this order will be pending as price is below Rs 100 and execution will happen only when price has reached or crossed Rs 100. Hence your stop-loss order was not executed. Due to this reason, we recommend keeping a sufficient gap between the trigger price and limit price to increase the chances of Stop Loss execution during high volatility. Note: In order to increase the chances of execution, we keep the default value of the limit price 2 ticks away from the trigger price. This is done so that if the LTP moves rapidly after triggering the order, the limit price shouldn’t be a hindrance and the order should still get executed. Also, if you change the pre-set limit price and bring it closer to the Trigger Price, the chances of execution can reduce in cases of volatility."
  },
  {
    "question": "My stop-loss order got triggered even though the predefined Trigger Price had not appeared. Why?",
    "answer": "Chances are that the market price did hit the stop-loss price, albeit momentarily and without you being able to spot it at that moment. Within a second, prices can change multiple times and not all of them are relayed to the Brokers by Exchange, especially during high volatility. As a result, such momentary price fluctuations are not seen anywhere. Price matching and execution of the orders  is done by the Exchanges and not the Broker."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Stop Loss?",
    "answer": "Stop-loss is a tool that investors use to minimise the loss in a trade. Some traders define it as an advance order, which triggers an automatic closure of an open position when the stock price reaches the trigger price level. Stop loss helps minimise losses but also limit profits from a trade."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Trailing Stop Loss?",
    "answer": "A Trailing Stop-loss is an order that lets you set a maximum value or percentage of loss you can incur on a trade. If the securiy price rises or falls in your favour, the trigger price jumps with it at the set value or percentage. If the security price rises or falls against you, the trigger price stays in place depending on the nature of the order."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a Stop-loss get triggered?",
    "answer": "Stop-loss can be your real saviour during a volatile market condition. A price level set at the beginning of the trade allows traders to close their position automatically when the stop-loss is reached. Squaring off takes place at the next price available at the trigger price level and helps limit losses."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the 1% rule of trading?",
    "answer": "The 1% rule defines the maximum limit of risk one can take in a trade or the risk-per-trade. It implies adjusting your position so that total loss doesn’t cross 1% of your trade value when the stop-loss is triggered. The 1% rule helps avoid significant losses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use stop-loss in trading with the AngelOne Trading app?",
    "answer": "You can place a Stop loss order  in AngelOne mobile app by following the below simple steps: Visit the AngelOne app and select the stock to Buy/Sell Select quantity of the trade Set’ Trigger price’ Enter the price where you want to place stop-loss Confirm the stop-loss price, click on “Buy/Sell” and confirm the order"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check my repayment schedule online and retrieve my credentials?",
    "answer": "The repayment schedule is not available on the app. You can request your repayment schedule by: Emailing at: support@creditsaison-in.com Calling: 18001038961"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if I miss an EMI? Will ECS bounce charges be levied?",
    "answer": "Yes, if you miss an EMI, a bounce charge of INR 450 will be applied."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I get email/SMS reminders from the Banks before my EMI date?",
    "answer": "Lenders will send EMI reminders before the due date via call and WhatsApp."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I have the option of part prepayment of the loan? Are there any charges for it?",
    "answer": "No, part prepayment of the loan is not available currently."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I check my payment statement online?",
    "answer": "You can check your payment statement online under the ‘Loans’ tab. All details for verification, tracking, and managing your loans will be available there once the loan is approved."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if I don't pay back OR miss EMI repayments on the Loan?",
    "answer": "If you miss or fail to repay your EMIs on the loan, it can negatively affect your credit score and may lead to additional charges or legal action. We strongly urge you to avoid missing your loan monthly installment payments."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I pay my missed EMI or foreclose the loan?",
    "answer": "If your EMI is not cleared from your bank account via the auto debit E-NACH mandate on the due date due to inadvertent circumstances, you can pay it yourself through the Angel One app. Follow these steps: Open the Angel One app. Navigate to the loan pass book. Use the “Pay Now” section to make the payment via net banking or debit card. Alternatively, the EMI mandate will be represented for auto debit from your bank account. To foreclose the loan, you can also use the Angel One app to find the option to foreclose and complete the payment using the same methods."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change my bank account used for repaying the EMI?",
    "answer": "Presently, we do not have the feature to facilitate the change of the bank account used to set up the EMI mandate. We urge you to continue servicing your EMI through the bank account that was used at the time of loan disbursement."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I foreclose my loan?",
    "answer": "Your eligibility for foreclosure varies depending on the lender partner. Please check your loan documents for specific details regarding foreclosure eligibility and conditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I check if I am eligible to apply for a personal loan?",
    "answer": "Currently, Angel One is offering personal loans via its lending partners to a select group of existing users only. We will gradually be rolling out the product to more users. Stay tuned for updates!"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum sum of money that I can borrow?",
    "answer": "The amount you can borrow depends on your profile. Currently, the maximum loan amount offered is Rs 5 Lakhs."
  },
  {
    "question": "What documents will I have to submit when applying for a personal loan?",
    "answer": "When applying for a personal loan, you may need to submit the following documents: Aadhaar and PAN for KYC approval Bank account details for cash disbursal Selfie and signature for user identification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add a prepaid amount of EMI in principal instead of Interest?",
    "answer": "No, this option is not available currently."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do I get the loan application form?",
    "answer": "Once you go to the loans tab on our Angel One platform, you will see the loan application form there. Please note: Only Angel One eligible customers will see the loans tab on our platform."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I apply for a joint loan with my spouse?",
    "answer": "No, we do not allow joint loan applications."
  },
  {
    "question": "I live out of the country and work from a remote location, will I be eligible for a personal loan?",
    "answer": "No, we only disburse personal loans to Indian citizens currently residing in India."
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm an NRI. Can I avail of a personal loan?",
    "answer": "No, we only disburse personal loans to Indian citizens currently residing in India."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use my Angel One holdings as collateral for availing of personal loans?",
    "answer": "No, we do not permit using collateral for availing personal loans."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much interest will I be charged?",
    "answer": "The interest rate and applicable EMIs are shown to you during the loan application process before you avail the loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can a NACH/eNACH setup help?",
    "answer": "NACH/eNACH Mandate is a repayment service that automates monthly recurring payments, such as loan EMIs. This setup ensures that: Your monthly EMIs are automatically collected from your bank account on the due date. You don’t miss any EMI payments, helping you maintain a good credit history. It simplifies the repayment process, saving you time and effort."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any advantages in applying for a personal loan online?",
    "answer": "Yes, applying for a personal loan online offers several advantages: Convenience : You can apply from anywhere with just a few clicks. Quick Processing : Submit necessary documents online and get money in your account within the same day. Seamless Experience : The entire process is smooth and efficient, saving you time and effort."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any offer for women/senior citizens?",
    "answer": "No, there are no special offers for women or senior citizens. However, if you have a good history with Angel One, we may provide attractive offers to you."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is prepayment allowed for personal loans?",
    "answer": "No, prepayment is not allowed for personal loans at the moment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I change my EMI due date?",
    "answer": "No, you cannot change your EMI due date once the loan is approved and disbursed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I change my EMI date once the loan EMI has started?",
    "answer": "No, there is no option to change the EMI date currently."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the personal loan disbursed?",
    "answer": "Once your loan application is approved, the loan amount will be disbursed to your registered bank account within 24 hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any balance transfer offer on a personal loan? Are there any benefits to this balance transfer?",
    "answer": "No, there is no balance transfer option available for personal loans currently."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum tenure of loan?",
    "answer": "The loan tenure at Angel One varies based on the customer’s profile. We thoroughly assess each user’s profile to determine the most suitable tenure."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the processing fee for a loan?",
    "answer": "The processing fee depends on your profile and will be specified during the application process."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I track my loan application?",
    "answer": "You can track your loan application under the ‘Loans’ tab in the Angel One app. All necessary details for verification, tracking, and managing your loan will be available there."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I need to provide collateral for a personal loan?",
    "answer": "No, you do not need to provide collateral for a personal loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are personal loan interest rates fixed or floating?",
    "answer": "Our lending partners charge a fixed interest rate for personal loans. This means your EMI amount remains the same every month throughout the loan tenure."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the fees? Why should I pay them? Are there hidden fees?",
    "answer": "All applicable charges are clearly shown in the Loan Agreement, Sanction Letter, and Key Fact Statement (KFS). Please read these documents carefully while accepting the loan terms and conditions during the application process. There are no hidden fees."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any restriction for usage of the loan amount or can I use it to pay up any other loan?",
    "answer": "You can use the personal loan amount at your discretion, including paying off other loans. However, it is crucial to use the loan for legal purposes and ensure timely repayment to avoid any serious actions against you."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does CIBIL affect my loan approval process?",
    "answer": "We check your CIBIL score to determine your eligibility for a personal loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the foreclosure process, and is there a minimum lock-in period?",
    "answer": "There is no lock-in period for foreclosure. You can initiate foreclosure through the app."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the foreclosure charges for a loan?",
    "answer": "Foreclosure charges, or full prepayment charges, depend on the lender. Specific details will be provided by your lender."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I get a top-up loan after taking a personal loan?",
    "answer": "No, we are still working on that product."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I have to pay any additional charges for foreclosure?",
    "answer": "Yes, foreclosure charges will be levied. These charges vary depending on factors such as the loan amount and tenure. The charges tend to be higher if you choose to close your loan earlier."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a credit report and score?",
    "answer": "Credit Report: A credit report is a detailed record of your credit history and financial behaviour. It includes information about: Your credit accounts Payment history Outstanding debts Inquiries made by lenders Credit Score: A credit score is a numerical representation of your creditworthiness based on the information in your credit report."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the factors that affect my credit score?",
    "answer": "Your credit score is influenced by several factors: Payment History : Consistency in repaying debts on time. Credit Utilisation : The ratio of your current credit card balances to your credit limits. Length of Credit History : The duration of your credit accounts. Types of Credit : A mix of different types of credit accounts (e.g., credit cards, loans). Recent Credit Inquiries : Number of recent applications for new credit."
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the terms settlement, default, and closed mean? Do they affect my credit score?",
    "answer": "1. Settlement : Occurs when you negotiate with a creditor to pay less than the full amount owed. It resolves the debt but is noted on your credit report. Can negatively impact your credit score. 2. Default : Happens when you fail to make required payments on time, breaching the loan agreement. Significantly harms your credit score. May lead to legal actions or collections. 3. Closed : Refers to an account that has been fully paid off and is no longer active. Can affect the length of your credit history, which is a factor in credit scoring. All three terms can impact your credit score: Settlements and defaults : Negatively impact your score. Closed accounts : Indirectly influence your score by affecting the length of your credit history."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Annual Percentage Rate (APR)?",
    "answer": "The Annual Percentage Rate (APR) represents the overall annual cost of a loan as a percentage. It includes the interest rate and additional charges like processing fees. APR provides a clear understanding of the true borrowing cost, helping you comprehend your actual loan expenditure."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Client Master List?",
    "answer": "Client Master List (CML) is a document with details of your DEMAT account providing your information such as name, address, DOB, bank account, nominations etc. To know about Client Master List “ Click Here “"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I get a copy of my Client Master List (CML)?",
    "answer": "While we dont have reports yet. We are working on it to make it avaible to you ASAP. You can follow our product updated on our blog."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Dividend?",
    "answer": "Dividend is the amount paid by a company to its shareholders out of its profits. To know more about dividend payment click here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "I have not received Dividend for the shares that I am holding in my demat account. What should I do?",
    "answer": "If you hold your shares in your Demat account on record date then the dividend will be credited to your bank account. However, if those shares are in Pool account, then the dividend will be credited to your Angel One ledger. The dividend is generally paid 30-45 days after the record date. In case you do not receive the same post 90 days from the Record date you can check the status with the Registrar (RTA). You can find the details of the Registrar on the BSE India website by visiting the Corp Information section."
  },
  {
    "question": "When and where will the dividend amount be credited?",
    "answer": "The dividend will be credited directly to your bank account after 30 to 45 days from the record date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will I be eligible for a dividend?",
    "answer": "If you have holdings in your account as of ex-date, you are eligible to receive dividends."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any charges or deductions on dividends?",
    "answer": "No, there are no charges or deductions on the dividend you receive."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check the dividends?",
    "answer": "You can create a watchlist by following these steps. Visit the Portfolio screen. Click on the specific stock that you are holding. Scroll to the bottom of screen to find the dividend earned on the stock. On web, click on the 3 dots that appear when you choose a stock. You will see an option to see the dividend earned. Please note that you will receive the dividend directly to your bank statement within 30-45 days from the date of dividend payment from the company."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check brokerage and other charges in my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can check the charges by clicking ‘Trades & Charges’ on the ‘Account Section’ of the app. Here, you can see both trade and non-trade charges (including charges by Angel One and external charges). Click here to know more about all the applicable charges."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the brokerage charges for different securities?",
    "answer": "Equity delivery: From 1 November 2024, Angel One charges brokerage of ₹20 or 0.1% per executed order whichever is lower (minimum brokerage of ₹2) for equity delivery trades. Equity intraday: For equity intraday, a brokerage charge of ₹20 or 0.03% per executed order whichever is lower will be applicable. Futures and Options: For F&O, ₹20 per executed order will be applicable as brokerage. Please click here to view all the latest charges applicable to your trades."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I see today’s charges?",
    "answer": "The charges for today’s trades will be updated in your account after 1-2 working days. This is because, the charges from regulators or external charges are settled at the end of trading day. Angel One receives those charge details from regulators and updates them in a couple of days. You will be able to check the charges by visiting Account → Trades & Charges screen on the platform."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any brokerage charges on delivery trades?",
    "answer": "From 1 November 2024, brokerage charges for equity delivery trades will be levied at flat INR 20 or 0.1%+ GST whichever is lower per executed order (minimum brokerage of INR 2 will be levied)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I see charges on delivery trades? I thought it was free.",
    "answer": "From 1 November 2024, brokerage charges for equity delivery trades will be levied at flat INR 20 or 0.1%+ GST whichever is lower per executed order (minimum brokerage of INR 2 will be levied). Additionally, there will be regulatory charges such as STT, GST, Stamp duty, etc. charged by the exchanges. These charges are the same for all trading platforms. You can see what Angel One charged you by visiting Account → Trades and charges → Total charges or View the detailed charges screen on the Angel One platform."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any charges on using Trade One feature?",
    "answer": "No, Trade One feature is completely free."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to use Trade From Charts functionality on Angel One web app?",
    "answer": "Please find the details of Trade from Charts functionality in this article ."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to track open orders and positions on charts ?",
    "answer": "Please visit this link for detailed guidance on tracking open orders and positions on charts"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to place Direct and Instant Orders on charts ?",
    "answer": "Please refer to this article ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are DP charges at Angel One?",
    "answer": "Depository Participant (DP) charges are combined charges imposed by CDSL and Angel One on every sell transaction of equity delivery shares. Please note that DP charges are not applicable on intraday trades or delivery buy transactions . The details are as below. Equity delivery : Rs. 20+GST per sale transaction, split as below. (Male – INR 3.5 (CDSL) + INR 16.5 (Angel One Charge)) (Female – INR 3.25 (CDSL) + INR 16.75 (Angle One Charge)) For example, If you sell 100 shares of TCS on Monday at 10 am and again sell 50 shares later in the day, DP charges will be applicable twice. The total DP charges levied in this case will be Rs. 47.2."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the timings for Intraday Square-Off?",
    "answer": "Below are the timings for Intraday Square-Off: Equity Segment: 3:15 pm Futures Options Segment: 3:20 pm Currency Segment: 4:45 pm Commodity Segment: 11:15/11:45 pm ( Depending on Daylight Savings Time)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was my position squared off?",
    "answer": "Your position could have been squared off due to any of the below reasons: Intraday trades will auto squared off at 3:15 pm for the Cash segment and at 3:20 for the F&O segment. Intraday trades will be squared off if you lose 80% of your Available Margin. When you don’t maintain the minimum required margin in your account your shares will be squared off 4 days after the shortfall occurs. When your shares bought using Margin are down by more than 50% of your fund balance, square-off will be done on the next trading day. Shares bought under Margin Product need to be fully paid or pledged, failing which the shared will be squared off after 7 days. If your account goes under debit/negative balance, then your shares will be squared off after 7 days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was my Intraday Position not squared off?",
    "answer": "Your buy/sell position might not be squared off due to upper/lower circuit in that stock. In case you have bought the stock and the share is in a lower circuit your shares will be sold the next day. In case you have short sold the share there is in upper circuit on the share the shares will be auctioned."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I need to verify my mobile number?",
    "answer": "Verifying your mobile number helps us create a secure account for you, ensuring a smooth app experience and the safety of your account."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I continue if the mobile number linked to my bank is different from the one registered with the app?",
    "answer": "No, your details, including your mobile number, must match those verified by our banking partner. A mismatch will result in your application being rejected by the bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are permissions to send SMS and access phone state required?",
    "answer": "These permissions are needed to verify your mobile number by sending an SMS. Rest assured, these permissions are used solely for verification purposes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I link any SIM for FD purchase if I have a dual SIM phone?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can. However, we recommend using the SIM registered with your bank account for authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I retry the registration if it was not successful earlier?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can retry. Ensure you use the SIM linked to your bank account for authentication."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I invest in FD if I do not have a PAN?",
    "answer": "No, currently, we only process fixed deposit requests for individuals with an active PAN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my PAN not getting verified?",
    "answer": "For booking fixed deposits, we need to verify your PAN with the regulated authorities. If there is a mismatch, the booking cannot be completed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if the name shown against my PAN is incorrect and I can't update it?",
    "answer": "The name linked to your PAN should be accurate for successful identity verification and KYC purposes. Please update your name to match your PAN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my Aadhar required?",
    "answer": "Aadhar is mandatory for identification and KYC setup for your account, necessary for processing your FD request."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I need a physical copy of my Aadhar?",
    "answer": "No, a physical copy is not required. We use secure platforms like DigiLocker and CKYC for verifying your Aadhar and other documents."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is DigiLocker?",
    "answer": "DigiLocker is a government initiative under the Digital India project for storing and verifying documents like PAN card, driving license, Aadhar card, school marksheets, and insurance papers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if there's a name mismatch and I can't complete the step?",
    "answer": "For successful FD booking, the name on your Aadhar and PAN should match. Correct the details on either your PAN or Aadhar card and retry."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I add a new address as my current address?",
    "answer": "Use the “add” button on the address choice screen to add an address that is not listed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I can't change my permanent address?",
    "answer": "The address from your Aadhar is considered your permanent address. You may add or select your current address to proceed with the FD application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can my permanent address be the same as my current address?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can select your permanent address as your current address if they are the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is video KYC required?",
    "answer": "Video KYC is required to complete the KYC verification step as mandated by the RBI."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if I am not available during bank working hours?",
    "answer": "If you have made the payment, we will notify you when the bank officers are available. If video KYC is not completed within 3 days, your money will be refunded to your bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I complete the Video KYC?",
    "answer": "Video KYC is available from Monday to Saturday, 09:00 AM to 08:00 PM. We will notify you to complete the video KYC during these hours if pending."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if video KYC fails?",
    "answer": "You can retry during banking hours within 2 days of FD booking if your video KYC fails."
  },
  {
    "question": "How will I know the status of my video KYC?",
    "answer": "Your video KYC details are verified by bank officers, which may take up to 3 hours. Track the video KYC and FD confirmation status on the ‘My Investments’ tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I can't move to the next step and complete my KYC verification?",
    "answer": "Retry using the correct details. If it still doesn’t work, try again later. If the issue persists, raise a ticket with our support team for assistance."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are details related to occupation, income, and family required for FD booking?",
    "answer": "These details are required by the bank to create your fixed deposit and ensure communication if needed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my money deducted before video KYC?",
    "answer": "Your money is deducted before video KYC as it is the last step to verify your identity and book your FD. Your money is safe with the bank, and interest starts accumulating from the time of payment. In case of issues with VKYC, your money will be refunded within 7 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is required for completing a video KYC?",
    "answer": "Keep your PAN Card and a blank paper with a pen ready for the VKYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are SEBI Charges?",
    "answer": "SEBI charges are fees levied by SEBI for sale and purchase transactions in all types of securities."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if my payment was complete, but the FD status is not showing complete?",
    "answer": "It can take some time for the bank to verify your application. You will receive an SMS notification once the FD is approved, which can take up to 24 hours. You can also track the status on the app dashboard."
  },
  {
    "question": "I haven't received the FD advice yet. Where will it get delivered?",
    "answer": "The FD advice is usually delivered to your registered email ID within 7 days of successful FD booking. This document is directly shared by the bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see my ongoing investments?",
    "answer": "You can access your ongoing investments on the ‘My Investments’ page under the Ongoing Investments tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my FD rejected?",
    "answer": "The FD may be rejected due to a discrepancy in the information provided. You can retry with the correct details."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my order get rejected?",
    "answer": "Orders can get rejected due to multiple reasons including insufficient margin, incorrect use of order type, stock not available for trading, etc. Tap on Order History under Orders tab to find your Order Rejection reason"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my order get rejected with a message ‘member not allowed to place an order in this script’?",
    "answer": "This message means that the selected stock is restricted from trading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does it say \"New position not allowed?\"",
    "answer": "This happens when you place orders on low volume (Illiquid) contracts which are either long range or far month contracts. Trades in these positions are not allowed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What to do if my order got rejected as the stock is in square-off today?",
    "answer": "If the selected stock is in square-off today, you may not be able to trade in that share. You will be allowed sell/trade post the square off is completed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if my order got rejected due to insufficient funds?",
    "answer": "Your Orders will get Rejected if you do not have Available Margin to Trade. You can either add funds or decrease quantity of the order. You can also Increase margin by pledging your shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is margin shortfall / limit issue?",
    "answer": "Margin shortfall occurs when you hold onto positions in your trading account without having sufficient margin. Kindly ensure you have sufficient balance to avoid Margin shortage penalties."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I not able to trade in Sensex F&O?",
    "answer": "You might be facing this issue due to below reasons. You might not have activated the derivatives or F&O segment. To activate the derivatives segment, visit the Account → Profile → Segment subscription section on Angel One platform. If you have activated F&O segment, Trading in SENSEX Futures and Options is allowed. However, there are a few contracts that would be disabled for trading due to a lack of liquidity. The contracts are blocked/unblocked for trading depending on the Open Interest and Volume for the contract. As a result, intraday orders in BSE F&O segments are currently restricted. Moreover, you can currently only place limit orders on BSE F&O since the bid-ask spread for market orders could be wide. Further because of illquidity we have restricted trading in Bankex & Sensex50 ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I not able to trade in BSE?",
    "answer": "You might be facing this issue due to below reasons. You might not have activated the derivatives or F&O segment. To activate the derivatives segment, visit the Account → Profile → Segment subscription section on Angel One platform. If you have activated F&O segment, Trading in SENSEX Futures and Options is allowed. However, there are a few contracts that would be disabled for trading due to a lack of liquidity. The contracts are blocked/unblocked for trading depending on the Open Interest and Volume for the contract. As a result, intraday orders in BSE F&O segments are currently restricted. Moreover, you can currently only place limit orders on BSE F&O since the bid-ask spread for market orders could be wide. Further because of illquidity we have restricted trading in Bankex & Sensex50."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I getting RMS rule error?",
    "answer": "You might be facing this issue due to below reasons. You might not have activated the derivatives or F&O segment. To activate the derivatives segment, visit the Account → Profile → Segment subscription section on Angel One platform. If you have activated F&O segment, Trading in SENSEX Futures and Options is allowed. However, there are a few contracts that would be disabled for trading due to a lack of liquidity. The contracts are blocked/unblocked for trading depending on the Open Interest and Volume for the contract. As a result, intraday orders in BSE F&O segments are currently restricted. Moreover, you can currently only place limit orders on BSE F&O since the bid-ask spread for market orders could be wide. Further because of illquidity we have restricted trading in Bankex & Sensex50 ."
  },
  {
    "question": "I am unable to buy or sell on BSE Sensex.",
    "answer": "You might be facing this issue due to below reasons. You might not have activated the derivatives or F&O segment. To activate the derivatives segment, visit the Account → Profile → Segment subscription section on Angel One platform. If you have activated F&O segment, Trading in SENSEX Futures and Options is allowed. However, there are a few contracts that would be disabled for trading due to a lack of liquidity. The contracts are blocked/unblocked for trading depending on the Open Interest and Volume for the contract. As a result, intraday orders in BSE F&O segments are currently restricted. Moreover, you can currently only place limit orders on BSE F&O since the bid-ask spread for market orders could be wide. Further because of illquidity we have restricted trading in Bankex & Sensex50 ."
  },
  {
    "question": "I am getting exchange not enabled error. What could be the possible reasons?",
    "answer": "This error occurs if a particular segment is not activated for user. If you have applied for activating a segment but still getting this error, it generally happens because of two conditions. In NFO if income proof is not submitted. In MCX if electronic contract note (ECN) is not submitted. To know more about how to activate F&O or Commodity segment, visit Account → Profile → Segment subscriptions in your web or mobile platform. You will be able to see which all segments are active and submit activation request online."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I getting PAN card invalid issue?",
    "answer": "This could be because of PAN and Aadhar not being linked. If you have already linked both, please check this article . It can take up to 10 days for CDSL to update Angel One on your PAN Aadhar linking status. Kindly wait for few more days for the update to take effect in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "I am getting “PAN card not linked to Aadhar” issue. But I have already linked both",
    "answer": "If you have already linked both, please check this article . It can take up to 10 days for CDSL to update Angel One on your PAN Aadhar linking status. Kindly wait for few more days for the update to take effect in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "My order is getting rejected because of PAN card invalid issue?",
    "answer": "This could be because of PAN and Aadhar not being linked. If you have already linked both, please check this article . It can take up to 10 days for CDSL to update Angel One on your PAN Aadhar linking status. Kindly wait for few more days for the update to take effect in the system."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is subscription plan?",
    "answer": "A subscription plan is a tailored package designed for our clients that provides exclusive trading benefits. These benefits vary depending on the plan and include zero brokerage trades, reduced interest rates on Margin Trading Facility (MTF), and combination offers. Plans are purchased with an upfront payment and are valid for a predetermined period, with specific usage limits attached."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I purchase a subscription plan?",
    "answer": "To purchase a subscription plan, navigate to Subscription Tab on Homepage or Account section then navigate to the ‘Discover Plans’ tab, select a plan to view its details, and click the ‘Buy’ button in the details page. After successful payment, the plan will be activated immediately during market hours or the next day if purchased after market hours. Please note that the subscription plans might not be available for some users."
  },
  {
    "question": "What payment methods are available to purchase a subscription plans?",
    "answer": "We accept several payment methods for purchasing subscription plans, including UPI, Google Pay, and PhonePe, all of which must be linked to your registered bank account with AngelOne."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my plan be activated after I purchase a subscription?",
    "answer": "Your subscription plan will be activated on the same day if the purchase is made within market hours. If bought post market hours, it will activate on the next day. The subscription period starts from the activation date and lasts for the duration specified in the plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I cancel my subscription plan?",
    "answer": "Clients wishing to cancel a subscription plan must submit a support ticket. It may take 3-7 days to process the cancellation request. Once the request is submitted, plan benefits will no longer be available. And if eligible you might get a refund for the subscription plan basis your utilisation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will I get a refund if I cancel my subscription plan?",
    "answer": "If you are eligible for a refund, based on the usage of your plan benefits and the Terms and Conditions of the subscription, the refund will be processed directly into your trading balance. The refund amount will be determined by the extent of plan utilization at the time of cancellation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see my active subscription plans?",
    "answer": "Your active subscription plans are displayed in two places: Under the ‘Your Plans’ tab in the Subscription Plan section, accessible from the homepage or your account section. At the top of the ‘Discover Plans’ tab, where an ‘Active Plans’ section highlights all the plans currently active for you."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can we see the complete list of securities under ASM/GSM?",
    "answer": "The ASM and GSM lists change from time to time. You can see or download the current securities list from the table below. Exchange Category NSE ASM Stocks NSE GSM Stocks BSE ASM Stocks BSE GSM Stocks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does Angel One allow buying and selling of scrips under ASM and GSM?",
    "answer": "Yes, we allow buying and selling of scrips under ASM and GSM, owing to certain rules and regulations. At Angel, trading is allowed in ASM scrips, while in the case of GSM, only scrips categorised under 0 and 1 are allowed for trading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is a particular scrip or scrips blocked from trading?",
    "answer": "To safeguard the clients from undue loss arising due to monitoring price and volatility and detecting misleading activities such as insider trading, fictitious transactions, and more, particular scrip and scrips are blocked from trading."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much margin is charged for ASM/GSM scrip?",
    "answer": "The applicable margin while placing orders for ASM/GSM scrip will be 100% in all stages while the price band fluctuates. For GSM: In Stage 1, the applicable margin shall be 100%, while, from Stage 2 onwards, an Additional Surveillance Deposit of 50% or 100% will be applicable based on GSM stage. Note: Please know that clients will not be able to buy stocks that are in stage 2 of GSM or higher. These stocks will require Additional Surveillance Deposit (ASD) of 100% of the trade value or more and this margin will remain blocked by the exchange atleast for 2 months even after the stock is solid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I trade in scrips categorized as unsolicited?",
    "answer": "No, trading in unsolicited scrips is restricted at Angel One. Click here to know more unsolicited investment tips."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code (IBC) and Inter Creditor Agreement (ICA)? What happens when a stock is under the surveillance of either of these codes?",
    "answer": "Insolvency Bankruptcy Code (IBC): This law is incorporated to handle insolvency and bankruptcy cases. When a stock is under surveillance for IBC, it means the company is going through an insolvency procedure. For some of these stocks, trading may still be allowed subject to the stage of surveillance. Inter Creditor Agreement (ICA): An agreement between various lenders and a single borrower that describes their rights and obligations in case of a default is ICA. When a company has entered into ICA to restructure the debt, its stock comes under the surveillance. In these cases, trading in the stocks might be allowed but with certain restrictions in place."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are some scrips blocked from trading in Options?",
    "answer": "Trading is resticted for certain scrips to protect clients from undue loss arising due to liquid counters."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to buy/sell SME shares?",
    "answer": "If the client has bought SME shares through IPO, selling is allowed. However, buying is completely blocked as per the risk and management decision to safeguard clients from undue losses occuring due to liquid counters."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I allowed to buy/sell limited quantity?",
    "answer": "Buying/selling is limited to a particular quantity due to illiquid counters and dry volumes. This restriction also safeguards clients from excess losses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are certain scrips allowed to trade only 2 times in a financial year?",
    "answer": "This criteria is removed from Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Penal/Delayed payment charges?",
    "answer": "Delayed Payment Charges (DPC) are the charges levied to clients; on the overall ledger debit from Trading day +2."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Delayed payment?",
    "answer": "Delayed Payment charges are billed at an interest rate of 18% p.a on the debit amount."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will Delayed payment charges (DPC) be charged to me?",
    "answer": "Delayed payment charges on the debit amount will be charged to you on a daily basis. However the same will be updated in your ledger every 15 days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check the breakup of the Interest charged to me?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your screen. Click on Statement Click on the transaction in which Interest is charged Click on View details to see the Interest charges break-up for your account"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a surveillance measure?",
    "answer": "Market surveillance plays a key role in ensuring safety and integrity of the markets as it the process of prevention and investigation of abusive, manipulative or illegal trading practices in the securities markets. Surveillance Measure is an initative by the regulatory bodies and exchanges to protect traders and investors by monitoring price and volatility and detecting misleading activities like insider trading, fictitious transactions, and more."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ASM?",
    "answer": "SEBI (Securities and Exchange Board of India) along with the stock exchanges have initiated an Additional Surveillance Measure or ASM to safeguard investors’ interests by ensuring there are no market speculations or manipulations like unexpected price movements. The stocks are categorized under ASM for surveillance based on criteria specified by NSE here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is GSM?",
    "answer": "GSM or Graded Surveillance Measure is a system used by Indian Stock Exchanges like NSE and BSE to alert traders/investors and ask them to be extra cautious while dealing in certain securities which have been categorized under GSM. Scrips can be classified under GSM due to abnormal price hike that doesn’t match with the company’s financial health, are illiquid, have negligible market capital, and are underpreforming."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between ASM and GSM?",
    "answer": "The main aim of the ASM framework is to control stock volatility, while the primary objective of GSM is to protect the investors from underperforming stocks by not allowing intraday trading and to advise them to be extra vigilant while dealing with securities that are witnessing unusual price fluctuations. Both these frameworks are introduced with different objectives, but their main goal is to protect traders and investors."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the basis of categorizing a scrip under ASM?",
    "answer": "SEBI and Exchanges jointly decides the objective criterion to shortlist securities under ASM based on the following parameters: 1. High Low Variation 2. Client Concentration 3. Close to Close Price Variation 4. Market Capitalization 5. Volume Variation 6. Delivery Percentage 7. No. of Unique PANs & PEs"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will a scrip be classified under GSM?",
    "answer": "On the basis of below-mentioned pointers, Regulatory Body and the Exchanges make their decision of adding a scrip under GSM category: 1. Periodic Call Auction Session for Illiquid Securities 2. Periodic Review of Movement of Securities to/from Trade for Trade 3. Persistent Noise Creators 4. Rumour Verification and Clarification in case of Spurt in Price/Volume"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will a scrip get out of ASM/GSM?",
    "answer": "Every 2 months in the case of ASM and every quarter in the case of GSM, the stock can go in and out of the list based on the review carried out by the exchange."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the surveillance measures under ASM?",
    "answer": "Please find the detailed surveillance measures under ASM here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Stock SIP?",
    "answer": "Stock SIP is a tool that helps you create wealth, by regularly investing small amounts in stocks & ETF’s of your choice as per your risk profile. To know more about Stock SIP Click Here"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the frequency of Stock SIP?",
    "answer": "The frequency for Stock SIP is Daily, Weekly or Monthly."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my Stock SIP orders be placed?",
    "answer": "Your Stock SIP orders will be placed between 11:00 am to 1:00 pm on the SIP day on a best-effort basis."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any additional charges for Stock SIP?",
    "answer": "There are no additional charges for Stock SIP. However, you will be charged the normal brokerage as per your brokerage plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "From where will my funds be debited for my Stock SIP order?",
    "answer": "Funds will be debited from your Angel One ledger for your Stock SIP order on the SIP debit date. Please maintain sufficient balance in your Angel One Ledger on the SIP debit date."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I place a Stock SIP Order?",
    "answer": "Tap on Stock SIP in the Tools Option on the Home page Add the stock for which you want to create a SIP Enter the amount, start date, frequency & click on Create Stock SIP Your Stock SIP will be successfully created"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I cancel my Stock SIP order?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of the page. Click on Stock SIP & select the SIP you wish to cancel Tap on cancel SIP & submit Your Stock SIP will be successfully cancelled"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my trading balance not updated even after adding funds successfully?",
    "answer": "If your trading balance is not updated after a successful fund addition, it could be due to the following reasons: High Volume of Requests : When there is a high volume of fund addition requests, it might take some time to update your balance. Please wait for 15 minutes. Bank Account Issues : Ensure you add funds from the bank account registered with Angel One, and the account should be in your name. If funds are added from an unregistered bank account, the amount might get deducted but will be credited back in 3-4 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds to your Angel One account due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You might be trying to add funds from a bank account not registered with your Angel One account. Incorrect UPI ID : The UPI ID used for fund addition might not be mapped to the bank account registered with Angel One. Ensure you add funds from your bank account registered with Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds using UPI?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds via UPI due to the following reasons: Bank Account Mismatch : The bank account linked with Angel One is different from the one selected in the UPI app. Unregistered UPI ID : Your UPI ID is mapped to a bank account that is not registered with Angel One. Timeout : Your UPI request on the app was not accepted within 10 minutes. Transfer Limit Exceeded : Your UPI transfer limit set by your bank is exhausted. Daily Limit Reached : Your daily UPI transaction limit is reached across all UPI apps. Insufficient Balance : You may have an insufficient balance in your bank account. Network Issues : Network failure at the bank’s/provider’s system. Incorrect UPI ID : Your UPI ID (VPA) entered is incorrect. Wrong UPI PIN : You have entered the wrong UPI PIN. Incorrect Method : You are transferring funds to Angel One’s UPI ID directly instead of using the ‘Add Funds’ option on the Angel One app/platform. Ensure you follow the correct procedure and check the above points to resolve the issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds using net banking?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds via net banking due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You are making payments from a bank account that is not registered with Angel One. Mismatched Bank Details : You have added different bank account details on the ‘Add Funds’ page and net banking page. Incorrect Credentials : You have entered incorrect credentials on the bank’s net banking page. Insufficient Balance : You have insufficient balance in your bank account to make the transaction. Transaction Limits : Your bank has placed limits on your transaction amount or the number of transactions. Network Failure : There may be a network failure at the bank’s or provider’s system. Ensure you check these points and follow the correct procedure to add funds via net banking."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the different options available to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can add funds using any of the following options. Add funds using payment apps such as PhonePe, Google Pay, etc. Add funds using UPI ID. Add funds using net banking. Please make sure to add funds from your bank account registered with Angel One in all the above options."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add funds from any bank account to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "No, you can add funds only from your bank account registered with Angel One. This is in accordance with SEBI guidelines. You cannot add funds from a bank account that belongs to your spouse, friend, or anyone else."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can add funds online to your Angel One account by following these steps: Tap on Account at the bottom of your screen. Click on Add Funds . Enter the amount and choose the mode of transfer (Google Pay, PhonePe, other UPI methods, or Net banking). Follow the subsequent steps to authorize your transaction, and the funds will be added to your account. Click here for more details on adding funds."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it mandatory to add funds via bank account registered with Angel One?",
    "answer": "Yes, as per regulatory guidelines and compliance norms, it is mandatory to transfer funds through the bank accounts registered with Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my amount debited from bank but not added to my trading balance?",
    "answer": "If the amount is debited from the bank but not added to your Angel One balance, it could be due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You might have tried to add funds from an unregistered bank account. The debited amount will be credited back to your bank in 3-4 working days. Technical Glitch : There could be a technical glitch at your bank’s end. The debited amount will be refunded in 3-4 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use debit/credit card to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You cannot add funds to your Angel One account using your debit or credit card. As per the regulatory guidelines, your transactions should be from a verified bank account. Also, the usage of credit cards is not allowed in the stock markets."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there a limit on the amount of funds that I can add to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "The limit for fund addition via UPI is 1 lakh per day. For net banking, the limit will be applicable as per the bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I download Profit & loss (P&L) statements?",
    "answer": "You can download the P&L statements from the last two years by following these steps. Login to your Angel One account. Go to the Account section in the application. You will find the Profit and Loss section on this screen. Click on it. You can see Profit & loss for the selected date range. Click on the download button. Choose the Detailed Tax P&L statement if you are filing ITR. Select the date range and click on download. Please note that you will also find short-term and long-term capital gains in tax P&L."
  },
  {
    "question": "My latest investment is not showing up in investments?",
    "answer": "Your Investments will appear in your ‘Investments’ Tab when your orders moves to ‘Completed’ section of your Orders Tab. This happens when we get the confirmation of Unit allotment by respective AMCs. This process generally takes 3/4 working days from order placement date. Your portfolio updation date in Order timeline is our estimate of when Unit allotment confirmation from AMC will come through. Please do not worry, This date date does not have any relation to your NAV date. Your NAV date depend on realization of funds by AMC."
  },
  {
    "question": "My Current value is not updated?",
    "answer": "our Current Value for mutual fund portfolio are calculated based by latest NAVs of funds held by you. Mutual fund NAVs (Net Asset Value) are updated every day after the market closes from Monday to Friday (All working days) This means that the Current value you see on a particular day reflects the exact current value as per previous working day. For example, on June 3rd, you will see the Current Value for June 2nd. The Current Value for June 3rd will be updated later on June 3rd, after the market closes. Therefore, throughout June 3rd, you will view the Current value from June 2nd. On June 4th, you will see Current Value of June 3rd. As Saturdays and Sundays are considered holidays (along with other market holidays), there are no updates to the Current values on these days as NAV does not change. However, certain special mutual funds (such as FoF) have their NAV updated once a week. So they current value might change if you hold these funds."
  },
  {
    "question": "My Mutual fund NAV is not updated",
    "answer": "Mutual fund NAVs (Net Asset Value) are updated every day after the market closes from Monday to Friday (All working days) This means that the NAV you see on a particular day reflects the value from the previous working day. For example, on June 3rd, you will see the NAV for June 2nd. The NAV for June 3rd will be updated later on June 3rd, after the market closes. Therefore, throughout June 3rd, you will view the NAV from June 2nd. On June 4th, you will see NAV of June 3rd. As Saturdays and Sundays are considered holidays (along with other market holidays), there are no updates to the NAV on these days. However, certain special mutual funds (such as FoF) have their NAV updated once a week. If you have any concerns about your mutual fund’s NAV is not being updated, please contact us."
  },
  {
    "question": "I got less money than what I placed an withdrawal order for?",
    "answer": "Your withdraw amount is converted to corresponding units while placing order at exchange. We calculate the units to be withdrawn based on current NAVs. Mutual fund NAVs (Net Asset Value) are updated every day after the market closes from Monday to Friday (All working days) For example, on June 3rd, you will see the NAV for June 2nd. Consider the following scenario for withdraw order placed on June 3rd: If NAV on 3rd June > 2nd June, You will receive an amount greater than order amount. If NAV on 3rd June < 2nd June, You will receive an amount lesser than order amount. In Summary, you will receive an amount according to latest NAV."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I import my external funds on Angel One?",
    "answer": "Importing external funds on Angel One is easy. Click on ‘All’ tab beside the Angel One tab on investment dashboard. Click on ‘Track External Funds’ and complete OTP verification on the OTP sent to your registered mobile no. Wait for a couple of minutes. You will be able to see all your investments with other brokers and track it on Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "My External funds portfolio is not updated?",
    "answer": "Your External funds investments displayed on Angel One does not consider any investments by you on other platforms after you import on Angel One. Your investments made before import are only considered. To update your portfolio click on the ‘Refresh’ button’."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see all my Active SIPs?",
    "answer": "You can view all your Active SIPs in the ‘SIPS’ section beside investments."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by “Signature Validation Issue” on Angel One?",
    "answer": "It could mean that for some reason, your signature could not be validated – it could be either because the signature itself was not valid or for some other reason. But not to worry! Our sales team will reach out to you shortly to help you resolve the issue and complete the KYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does “PAN Validation Issue” mean on Angel One?",
    "answer": "This means that there is currently an issue in the process of validating your PAN (Permanent Account Number). It could be because – The user’s “Aadhaar Name” and “Name of Authorized Person in the Income Tax Return (ITR)” are different. The OCR has failed to capture the PAN data – perhaps the PAN copy or the photograph on the PAN card of the applicant is not clear. It could also be because the PAN OCR is disabled. However, such issues can be overcome. Our sales team will reach out to you shortly and help you finish your KYC."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of “Selfie Validation issue” on Angel One?",
    "answer": "This means that your selfie could not be validated because – It did not match certain requirements Selfie matched with score 69 But don’t worry! Our sales team will reach out to you shortly and help you resolve the issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by “Name Mismatch issue” on Angel One?",
    "answer": "This means that there is currently an issue of mismatch among the names submitted in – PAN card and address proof or PAN card and bank proof. Our sales team will reach out to you shortly to provide you with the steps required hereafter to complete the KYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of “Address Proof Validation Issue”?",
    "answer": "This basically means that there is an issue in validating the address proof because – The PAN is non-KRA. The QR code on the Aadhaar (proof of address) is not clear. The Aadhaar OCR is disabled. The address proof is something other than Aadhaar or Digilocker. There is mismatch in the addresses submitted in the different documents But no worries! Our sales team will reach out to you shortly to provide you with the steps required hereafter to finish your KYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by “Bank Details Validation Issue” on Angel One?",
    "answer": "This means that there is an issue in the bank details validation process because – IMPS is not applicable. Could not perform penny drop verification. Our sales team will reach out to you shortly to help you complete the KYC process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my account get deactivated?",
    "answer": "Your account may become dormant/deactivated due to the following reasons: You have not done any financial transaction (trading, pay-in, etc) with Angel One for more than a year. If any of the following 6 profile details are missing: name, PAN, address, income range, mobile number, email id You have been debarred from trading by SEBI. There is an outstanding balance issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I reactivate my dormant account?",
    "answer": "To reactivate your account, login to the angel one app on your device or web using the link angelone.in/login Verify the login using otp sent to your registered mobile number, email Post otp verification, you will be shown the dormant status of your account along with the reason Click on “Reactivate Account” button Confirm your personal details and click on “proceed” You will be required to do the 2 factor authentication using your pan number registered with Angel One account Post successful 2FA verification, your request will be submitted and your account will be activated within 1-2 working days"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Securities Transaction Tax?",
    "answer": "Securities Transaction Tax is a direct tax charged on the purchase and sale of securities that are listed on stock exchanges. Buy and Sale of equity delivery shares: 0.1% per executed order Sale of equity intraday shares: 0.025% per executed order Sale of futures in securities: STT shall be revised to 0.02% from 0.0125% Sale of options in securities: STT shall be revised to 0.1% of premium from 0.0625%"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check my repayment schedule online and retrieve my credentials?",
    "answer": "The repayment schedule is not available on the app. You can request your repayment schedule by: Emailing at: support@creditsaison-in.com Calling: 18001038961"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if I miss an EMI? Will ECS bounce charges be levied?",
    "answer": "Yes, if you miss an EMI, a bounce charge of INR 450 will be applied."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I get email/SMS reminders from the Banks before my EMI date?",
    "answer": "Lenders will send EMI reminders before the due date via call and WhatsApp."
  },
  {
    "question": "Do I have the option of part prepayment of the loan? Are there any charges for it?",
    "answer": "No, part prepayment of the loan is not available currently."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I check my payment statement online?",
    "answer": "You can check your payment statement online under the ‘Loans’ tab. All details for verification, tracking, and managing your loans will be available there once the loan is approved."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if I don't pay back OR miss EMI repayments on the Loan?",
    "answer": "If you miss or fail to repay your EMIs on the loan, it can negatively affect your credit score and may lead to additional charges or legal action. We strongly urge you to avoid missing your loan monthly installment payments."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I pay my missed EMI or foreclose the loan?",
    "answer": "If your EMI is not cleared from your bank account via the auto debit E-NACH mandate on the due date due to inadvertent circumstances, you can pay it yourself through the Angel One app. Follow these steps: Open the Angel One app. Navigate to the loan pass book. Use the “Pay Now” section to make the payment via net banking or debit card. Alternatively, the EMI mandate will be represented for auto debit from your bank account. To foreclose the loan, you can also use the Angel One app to find the option to foreclose and complete the payment using the same methods."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change my bank account used for repaying the EMI?",
    "answer": "Presently, we do not have the feature to facilitate the change of the bank account used to set up the EMI mandate. We urge you to continue servicing your EMI through the bank account that was used at the time of loan disbursement."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I foreclose my loan?",
    "answer": "Your eligibility for foreclosure varies depending on the lender partner. Please check your loan documents for specific details regarding foreclosure eligibility and conditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Bonus Issue?",
    "answer": "Bonus shares are additional shares given by the company to existing shareholders, free of cost, in proportion to the shares held by the shareholder."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is eligible for bonus shares?",
    "answer": "Shareholders who own shares of the company on the record date set by the company are eligible for bonus shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will the Bonus shares be credited in my demat account?",
    "answer": "The bonus shares will get credited to your demat account 10-15 days after the record date. In case you do not receive the same post 15 days from the Record date you can check the status with the Registrar (RTA). You can find the details of the Registrar on the BSE India website by visiting the Corp Information section."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why has the average price of the stock reduced after receiving bonus shares?",
    "answer": "The buy price of bonus shares is zero, as they are credited at no cost. When the shares are credited to your account, the quantity of shares increases while the invested value remains unaffected. As a result, the average price of the stock reduces. Be assured that it is correctly calculated by Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Auto Square Off?",
    "answer": "The charges for Auto Square Off are Rs 20 per executed order."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was my loan application rejected even though I have a decent salary?",
    "answer": "Your loan application is evaluated based on multiple factors. While your salary is one aspect, other considerations include your credit score, existing debt, and our lender partners’ policies."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was my loan application rejected?",
    "answer": "Your application did not meet the requirements of our lender partners’ policies. Therefore, we are unable to offer you a loan at this time."
  },
  {
    "question": "My loan application was rejected. How can I reapply?",
    "answer": "You will need to wait at least 90 days before you can reapply for a loan after a rejection."
  },
  {
    "question": "If I have any complaints or concerns related to personal loans, what are the Grievance Redressal (Nodal) Officer details for Angel One and its lending partners?",
    "answer": "For grievances related to your loan facility, you can reach out to the Nodal Officer at Angel One: Name: Gable Fernandes Email: lendingsupport@angelbroking.com Phone No.: 1800 1020 Designation: Nodal Grievance Redressal Officer Address: 601 6th Floor, Ackruti Star, Central Road – MIDC, Andheri (E), Mumbai – 400 093 If you are not satisfied with the decision or have not received any response within the set timelines, you may escalate the issue following our escalation matrix stated on our website. For Kisetsu Saison India Private Limited (Credit Saison): Customers can provide feedback or send complaints through the following channels between 10:00 am and 6:00 pm, Monday to Friday (except on national holidays): Call Customer Service Helpline: 1800-1038-961 Email: support@creditsaison-in.com Write to: Kisetsu Saison Finance India Private Limited (Credit Saison) First Floor, IndiQube Lexington Tower Lexington Towers, Tavarekere Main Rd, Tavarekere, S.G. Palya, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560029 If the response received through the above channels is not satisfactory, you can approach the Complaints Redressal Officer: Name: Ms. Preethi Nair Email: preethi.nair@creditsaison-in.com"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I avoid giving the required consents?",
    "answer": "To ensure a smooth and secure onboarding process, we require certain permissions to fetch and validate your personal details and for KYC purposes. These permissions are only used for account creation and validation."
  },
  {
    "question": "How safe is it to share my data using consents?",
    "answer": "Your data is only used for account creation and KYC purposes, and it is not shared with any third parties. The safety of your information is our top priority."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is CKYC, and why do I need to consent to fetch CKYC data?",
    "answer": "CKYC stands for Central KYC (Know Your Customer), an initiative by the Government of India to streamline the KYC process by making all relevant information available in one place. With your consent, we can access this information for a faster and safer onboarding experience."
  },
  {
    "question": "What details will be accessed from Digilocker for FD booking?",
    "answer": "We will use the Digilocker facility to validate your identity and complete KYC by verifying documents like Aadhar and PAN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I open a Fixed Deposit if I am an Indian citizen but not a tax resident of India?",
    "answer": "Currently, we can only process fixed deposit requests for users who are tax residents of India."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a tax resident of India?",
    "answer": "A person is considered a resident of India if they have spent either: 182 days or more in India during the financial year, or 365 days or more in India during the four preceding years and 60 days or more during the current financial year."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Robo order?",
    "answer": "A Robo order is a multi-leg order used in intraday trading which allows you to place 2 more orders along with the initial order. One order is placed at a price lower than order price and other placed at a price higher than order price. Order is automatically exited when any of the defined targets are met. These orders can be exited manually before hitting target or stop loss targets as well."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place a Robo order on the NSE and BSE?",
    "answer": "Yes, Robo orders can be placed in both NSE and BSE"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which product type allows to place Robo Orders?",
    "answer": "You can place Robo orders only in Intraday."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I avail MTF facility for Robo order?",
    "answer": "No, the MTF facility is unavailable for Robo orders."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place Robo orders in commodities and currencies?",
    "answer": "Robo orders can only be placed in the cash market segment (Equity and Derivatives) for stocks and indices."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place a delivery order using Robo order?",
    "answer": "No, you cannot place a Robo order in Delivery trading."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place a Robo order in all stocks?",
    "answer": "Robo orders can be placed in selected scrips of cash segment for intraday trading. Robo orders can not be placed on low volume scrips."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place a Robo order at any time during the day?",
    "answer": "You can place a Robo order between 9:15 AM to 3:10 PM on a trading day."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if my Robo order does not get executed during the day?",
    "answer": "If your first-leg order (initial Limit order) doesn’t get executed during the market hours of the trading day, then the Robo order will get cancelled. If your first-leg order is executed and neither the second-leg nor the third-leg order gets executed your position will get auto-squared off at 3:10pm."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times a Robo order can be modified?",
    "answer": "Robo order can be modified in the following ways any number of times: Initial Order can be modified in cases the Order has not been executed. In case of Initial Order is executed, only Stop Loss & Target Orders can be modified. Once the Stop loss/Target price has been executed no modifications are possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to place a Robo order?",
    "answer": "Tap on Watchlist at the bottom of your screen Click on Buy/Sell & select Intraday Tap on Smart Orders & select Robo Order Enter the Quantity, price, stop Loss & target targets Click on Place Buy/Sell Order Your order would be placed successfully subject to fund availability"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to place robo order on desktop or web?",
    "answer": "Currently, we have robo order feature only on mobile app. We are working on bringing it to web as well."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for pledging and unpledging shares?",
    "answer": "A fixed transaction fee of ₹20 + GST is charged for each pledge and unpledge request, regardless of the number of shares. The split is as follows. INR 5 (Depository) + INR 15 (Angel One Charge) + GST For example, Suppose you want to pledge 100 shares of ABC Ltd. and 50 shares of XYZ Ltd. You will be charged ₹40 + GST for 2 requests, irrespective of the number of shares in each request. Similarly, if you want to place one unpledge request for 100 shares of ABC Ltd. and two unpledge requests for 50 shares and 20 shares of XYZ Ltd, respectively. In this case, you will be charged (₹20 x 3) = ₹60 + GST for 3 requests, irrespective of the number of shares in each request."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the different Charts interface available on Angel One?",
    "answer": "Android and IOS mobile app: Chart IQ and Trading View Web: Trading View only"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to interchange between Chart IQ and Trading View chart in Mobile App?",
    "answer": "On the Android and iOS mobile version, you can simply go to Account > Settings > Scroll down to Charts and choose between ChartIQ or TradingView. Note that you can change the chart version only on the mobile version and not the web application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Chart Price scale is changed to logarithmic values. How can i change it back to default settings?",
    "answer": "Follow these steps to adjust your price scale to regular: 1. Open the chart and check the price scale on the right-hand side of the chart. 2. Below it, you will find a settings icon (shaped like a sun). 3. Click this settings icon. 4. Thereafter, a menu with different options will appear. 5. Click on ‘Regular’ to bring the price scale back to the default setting."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I find Chart IQ?",
    "answer": "On the Angel One mobile app, you can find the Chart IQ interface by going to Account > Settings > Scroll down to Charts and choose ChartIQ. Please note that you can change the chart version only on the mobile version and not on the web app. We are working on making ChartIQ available on Web as well."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Chart IQ available on web?",
    "answer": "No, Chart IQ is not available on web as of today. Chart IQ is available only on mobile app. We are working on making it available to you on web soon."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place an order when markets are closed (AMO Order)?",
    "answer": "You can place AMO orders for the next trading day post market closure. AMO orders can be placed normally like a regular buy/sell order which are pushed to the exchange once the market opens."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Disclosed Quantity?",
    "answer": "Disclosed quantity feature allows you to declare only a part of the actual order to the market that you want to buy/sell. Once you specify the disclosed quantity, the order is sent to the exchange and only the disclosed part is shown on the market screen. The disclosed quantity should neither be equal to or greater than the order quantity nor should it be less than 10% of the order quantity."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I convert my F&O positions?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen Click on the Order that you wish to convert Tap on Convert Choose the Product Type & click Submit. Your Position will be converted successfully."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I modify my order?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen Click on Open Orders Tap on the Order you wish to modify & click on Edit Order You will be able to modify your Orders from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I buy / sell stocks?",
    "answer": "Tap on the share for which you want to place a Buy/Sell Order Click on Buy/Sell & Select the mode between Delivery, Margin & Intraday Enter Quantity, Price & click on Place Buy/Sell Order"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I convert my Intraday position into Delivery?",
    "answer": "As of now position conversion is not available in Angel Spark. Will add FAQ’s once its introduced PM Comment – It is allowed. Please check point number 6. Make a single point about conversion as the journey is the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I place a Stop Loss order for my existing position?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen Click on Positions Tap on the Order for which you wish to place a Stop Loss Tap on the stop loss button at the bottom of the screen Enter trigger price, price & click on place Buy/Sell Order"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is multi chart view available on both - web & mobile?",
    "answer": "No it is right now only available on web app."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to use Multi Chart functionality on Angel One web app?",
    "answer": "Please find the details of multi chart functionality in this artilcle ."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I compare multiple scrip/contract on the chart view?",
    "answer": "Multi Chart View Guide – We have introduced Multiple chart layout in our web app view as of now. Users can select the multiple chart layout from the select layout icon on the chart header. When we will select any scrip , it will get populated on the selected frame. Users can then compare different compare different scrip on a multi chart view."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is multi chart functionality free or paid?",
    "answer": "Multi chart feature is absolutely free on Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will the Stock Split impact be visible in my Portfolio?",
    "answer": "You will receive the Stock Split shares in 3-4 trading days after the record date. In case you do not receive the same post 5 days from the Record date you can check the status with the Registrar (RTA). You can find the details of the Registrar on the BSE India website by visiting the Corp Information section."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a stock split?",
    "answer": "Stock split is a corporate action in which a company issues more shares to its existing shareholders by reducing the face value of each share as predecided."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is stock consolidation?",
    "answer": "It is an action taken by a company where they reduce the number of outstanding shares by combining the shares as well as increasing the face value. It is also known as a reverse stock split ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are record and ex-split dates?",
    "answer": "The record date is the date on which the company checks its records to identify the eligible shareholders for a stock split. Please note that the record date and ex-date are the same. Ex- split date is the date on which the stock starts trading at the new adjusted split price."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I get my brokerage cashback?",
    "answer": "Brokerage Discount is offered to certain new customers for the first month only. Below are the Terms & Conditions: This is a one-time and exclusive offer for new customers and might not apply to all users. The validity of free brokerage is 30 days on all trades from the date of account opening, with an upper limit of ₹ 500. Brokerage will not be charged; it will simply be discounted if applicable on a certain trade. Please note: Angel One reserves the right, in its absolute discretion, to change, alter or discontinue the offer and shall communicate the same to the client via email."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I close or delete my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "We are sorry to hear that you want to close your account. You can click here to submit an account closure request or please follow the below steps. Navigate to the Profile section on the Account screen of the app. Scroll to the bottom of the screen and click on “ Close Demat and Trading Account ”. Read the disclaimer and proceed. Your account closure request will be processed in 3 working days . Please note that the account closure is permanent. Once it is closed, you can not open an account with Angel One within 90 days. We look forward to serving you again in the future."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I close my Angel One account temporarily?",
    "answer": "No, you can not close your account temporarily. Account closure is permanent. However, you can freeze your account, if you detect any suspicious activities."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I freeze my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can freeze your account by visiting the Profile page on the app. Scroll down and click on Temporary Account Freeze. Read the disclaimer and proceed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to submit an account closure request?",
    "answer": "To close your account, please make sure the below conditions are satisfied. No holdings in your portfolio No open positions No open trade No active SIPs No MF Units No active IPO order No pledge holdings No debit/credit in your account balance The above conditions should be satisfied for submitting an account closure request."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I close my Angel One account and reopen it later?",
    "answer": "Once you close your Angel One account, it is permanently closed. However, you can open a new demat account with Angel One after 90 days from the closure."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much time does it take to close my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "It will take up to 3 working days to close your account."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to close my Angel One account and transfer my holdings?",
    "answer": "We are sorry to hear that you want to close your account. You can click here to submit account closure request or please follow the below steps. Navigate to the Profile section on the Account screen of the app. Scroll to the bottom of the screen and click on “ Close Demat and Trading Account ”. Read the disclaimer and proceed. Your account closure request will be processed in 3 working days . Please note that the account closure is permanent. Once it is closed, you can not open an account with Angel One within 90 days. Note: If you want to close the account and transfer your holdings, please submit a request by uploading your CML copy of the DP where you want to transfer your holdings. The CML copy should be duly signed and stamped by the respective DP. We look forward to serving you again in the future."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between Limit and Market orders?",
    "answer": "In a Limit Order the buying price or sell price is specified and the trade is executed only when the price is met. In contrast, a Market Order gets executed at the current market price."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an Immediate or Cancel (IOC) order?",
    "answer": "In the case of Immediate or Cancel (IOC) order, the order has to be executed as soon as it is released in the market. It means that the buying or selling of the security happens almost immediately, and if it doesn’t, the order gets cancelled automatically."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do i place an GTT Order?",
    "answer": "Tap on the share for which you want to place a GTT Order Click on Buy/Sell & select “Delivery” Click on Smart Orders & Click on GTT order Enter the Trigger Price, Limit Price & click on “Create GTT”"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Stop Loss Orders?",
    "answer": "A stop-loss order is a buy/sell order that can help you limit your losses in case the prices move against your trade. If you are buying a stock, then you will have to add a sell stop-loss. If you have to sell a stock, then you will have to add a buy stop-loss."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Good Till Trigger Order(GTT)?",
    "answer": "GTT order allows you to place buy or sell orders at a predetermined price. These orders are executed if the market price of the stock reaches your specified price also called as Trigger Price before the GTT order expires. GTT Orders are valid for an year. If price is not reached within one year then order is cancelled"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the validity for GTT Order?",
    "answer": "GTT Order is a feature that allows you to Buy/Sell shares at your desired price with 1 year order expiry date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place an Intraday Order using GTT?",
    "answer": "GTT feature cannot be used for Intraday."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which segments can GTT Order be used for?",
    "answer": "GTT order can be used for Equity Cash segment under Delivery Margin Product Type NSE, MCX NCDEX derivatives GTT orders can be placed under Carry forward Product type."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my Limit Order get executed at market price?",
    "answer": "This might have happened if you have tried to sell at a price lower than the current market price OR buy at a price higher than current price. In such a situation, the system considers it as a market order and executes it at the current price."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was my stop loss order executed even though the price did not breach my trigger?",
    "answer": "Within a second multiple prices are received. Not all the price changes are shown on the application. It is possible that the price was breached but could not be shown on the application. This may have happened since you are able to see just one tick per second, you may not be able to see the price when the stop-loss limit is breached and the trade is executed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my market order in the pre-open session become a limit order?",
    "answer": "In the pre-open session, all unmatched market orders are carried over to the normal market with their original timestamp as limit orders at the equilibrium price. If the opening-price is not discovered, market orders will be carried over at the previous day’s closing price"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an Immediate or Cancel Order (IOC) order?",
    "answer": "In the case of an immediate or cancel order, the order has to be executed as soon as it is released in the market. It means that the buying or selling of the security happens almost immediately and if it doesn’t, the order gets cancelled automatically."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Delivery Order?",
    "answer": "Delivery Order means you buy some shares, and hold them in your demat account. You can hold them in your demat account as long as you want. Delivery orders are used for long term investments."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an Intraday Order?",
    "answer": "Intraday Order means buying/selling a security with the intention of exiting the position on the same day. You can exit the position whenever you want within the day. All the intraday orders are automatically squared off if left open."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an AMO Order?",
    "answer": "AMO orders are Orders that are placed post market closure. They can be placed similarly to regular orders. these orders are pushed to exchange on next trading day."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Limit Order?",
    "answer": "A limit order is an order to buy or sell a stock at a specific price. these orders are valid for a day. if price is not reached within the day, these orders are automatially cancelled."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Market Order?",
    "answer": "A market order is a buy or sell order to be executed immediately at the next price match. these orders are used when you want to buy/sell desired quantity as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Call and Trade facility? Are there any charges for this facility?",
    "answer": "Call and Trade facility allows you to place a trade by calling Angel One. Charges for Call Trade are Rs 20+GST (RS 23.60) per executed Order."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Margin Pledge?",
    "answer": "Margin Pledge also called stock pledge refers to the process of using your existing stocks as collateral for availing additional limits."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Margin Pledge?",
    "answer": "Pledging of shares is charged a flat transaction fee, irrespective of the quantity pledged. Hence, the fee charged is per scrip and not the volume. So, these charges remain the same whether you pledge 1 share or 100 shares. Charges per scrip are Rs 20+GST. The split is as below. INR 5 (Depository) + INR 15 (Angel One Charge) + GST"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Unpledging of shares?",
    "answer": "Unpledging of shares means release of pledge by paying off the loan amount or clearing your ledger debits & associated dues"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Unpledging of shares?",
    "answer": "Unpledging of shares are charged a flat transaction fee, irrespective of the quantity unpledged. Hence, the fee charged is per scrip and not the volume. So, these charges remain the same whether you un-pledge 1 share or 100 shares. Charges per scrip are Rs 20 +GST."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process for Margin Pledge?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your page Scroll down to Stock Pledging & click on Pledge stocks Click on Increase & select the quantity & shares you wish to pledge Click on Increase Margin Enter OTP by Angel One You will be redirected to the CDSL website where you need to enter the OTP sent by CDSL on your registered mobile number Post entering the OTP click on Verify Once the pledge is approved, margins will be provided against the pledged stock within 15 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see the status of my Margin Pledge request?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your page Scroll down to Stock Pledging & click on Pledge stocks Click on Margin Pledge Transactions You will be able to see your Margin Pledge transactions from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to Unpledge shares?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your page Scroll down to Stock Pledging & click on Pledge stocks Click on Withdraw & select the stocks that you need to Unpledge Click on Withdraw Margin The stocks will be Unpledged on T+1 day if margin requirements are fulfilled"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see the status of my Unpledge request?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your page Scroll down to Stock Pledging & click on Pledge stocks Click on Margin Pledge Transactions You will be able to see your Margin Unpledge transactions from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Goods & Service tax (GST) invoice?",
    "answer": "Stock brokers provide broking service, and hence are liable to pay Goods & Services tax, which is covered in the GST invoice"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the GST rate?",
    "answer": "The GST rate for Stock broking service is 18%."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Contract Note?",
    "answer": "A contract note is a confirmation of trades done on a particular day. To know more “ Click Here “"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I download the Contract note?",
    "answer": "You can download the day-wise contract note from our app. Follow the steps below. Go to the Account section on the App. Go to Statements Click on Trade executed You will find an option to download the contract note here. We also send you the contract note to your registered email ID."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are DP charges at Angel One?",
    "answer": "Depository Participant (DP) charges are combined charges imposed by CDSL and Angel One on every sell transaction of equity delivery shares. Please note that DP charges are not applicable on intraday trades or delivery buy transactions . The details are as below. Equity delivery : Rs. 20+GST per sale transaction, split as below. (Male – INR 3.5 (CDSL) + INR 16.5 (Angel One Charge)) (Female – INR 3.25 (CDSL) + INR 16.75 (Angle One Charge)) For example, If you sell 100 shares of TCS on Monday at 10 am and again sell 50 shares later in the day, DP charges will be applicable twice. The total DP charges levied in this case will be Rs. 47.2."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a fixed deposit and why should I invest?",
    "answer": "A fixed deposit (FD) is a popular and safe investment option in India. You invest a lump sum of money at an agreed interest rate and receive the amount along with interest upon maturity. The interest rates are fixed, higher than a regular savings account, and the investment is protected from market fluctuations."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it safe to invest in an FD?",
    "answer": "Yes, FDs are one of the safest investment options. Unlike market-led investments where returns fluctuate, the returns on an FD are fixed at the time of investment. Even if FD interest rates change over time, your FD will grow at the rate you initially booked."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is DICGC and which deposits are secured by them?",
    "answer": "The Deposit Insurance and Credit Guarantee Corporation (DICGC) is a wholly-owned subsidiary of the Reserve Bank of India (RBI). It insures bank deposits, including savings, current, recurring, and fixed deposits, up to Rs. 5 lakh per account holder per bank. This insurance does not cover FDs with NBFCs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can only banks offer fixed deposits?",
    "answer": "No, fixed deposits are offered by banks, NBFCs, and the India Post Office. FDs with NBFCs, known as Corporate FDs, often offer higher interest rates compared to banks."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an NBFC and do they also offer fixed deposits?",
    "answer": "A Non-Banking Financial Corporation (NBFC) operates as a financial institution without a full banking license, regulated by the Ministry of Corporate Affairs and the Reserve Bank of India. NBFCs offer services like savings, investment plans, lending schemes, insurance, and fixed deposits."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum and maximum amount I can invest in a fixed deposit?",
    "answer": "You can start investing in fixed deposits with a minimum amount as low as INR 5000. The maximum amount varies based on the specific FD scheme you choose."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it mandatory to add a nominee?",
    "answer": "No, it is not mandatory to add a nominee, but it is recommended."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add a nominee who is less than 18 years old?",
    "answer": "Yes, but you must provide the details of a guardian."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who can I add as a nominee?",
    "answer": "You can add any individual as a nominee, including family members, relatives, friends, or any trusted person."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add or change a nominee later?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can add or change a nominee later, but this service is currently available only with some partner banks. You will see the “Add Nominee” option on the dashboard once your FD is successfully booked."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is FD advice?",
    "answer": "FD advice is a computer-generated statement provided by the bank as proof of ownership or investment when you open a fixed deposit."
  },
  {
    "question": "I do not file taxes. Is there a way for TDS to not get deducted from the FD?",
    "answer": "Currently, we do not offer a solution to avoid TDS deduction. Some banks allow the filing of forms 15G/15H, but we do not have this functionality. TDS is deducted only if the total interest from all sources with the bank exceeds Rs 40,000 for normal citizens and Rs 50,000 for senior citizens."
  },
  {
    "question": "How are FDs taxed?",
    "answer": "Interest earnings from your fixed deposit are taxed according to your tax slab. For example, if you are in the 20% tax bracket and you earned Rs 6,000 interest from a 1-year FD of Rs 1 lakh at 6%, you will pay 20% of Rs 6,000, which is Rs 1,200, as tax."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Bonus Issue?",
    "answer": "Bonus shares are additional shares given by the company to existing shareholders, free of cost, in proportion to the shares held by the shareholder."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is eligible for bonus shares?",
    "answer": "Shareholders who own shares of the company on the record date set by the company are eligible for bonus shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will the Bonus shares be credited in my demat account?",
    "answer": "The bonus shares will get credited to your demat account 10-15 days after the record date. In case you do not receive the same post 15 days from the Record date you can check the status with the Registrar (RTA). You can find the details of the Registrar on the BSE India website by visiting the Corp Information section."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why has the average price of the stock reduced after receiving bonus shares?",
    "answer": "The buy price of bonus shares is zero, as they are credited at no cost. When the shares are credited to your account, the quantity of shares increases while the invested value remains unaffected. As a result, the average price of the stock reduces. Be assured that it is correctly calculated by Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I know my brokerage plan?",
    "answer": "You can check your brokerage plan in the Angel app. Navigate to the Account → Profile → Brokerage & Charges screen on the app. You will be able to see your brokerage plan and corresponding charges here."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my current brokerage plan?",
    "answer": "You can check your brokerage plan in the Angel app. Navigate to the Account → Profile → Brokerage & Charges screen on the app. You will be able to see your brokerage plan and corresponding charges here."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is buyback?",
    "answer": "It is a corporate action through which a company buys back its own shares from the holders, generally at a price higher than the market price. Click here to know more about the buyback of shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I apply for buyback of shares?",
    "answer": "Here’s how you can apply for a buyback of shares. You will receive a link from the RTA for applying for the buyback issue Fill in the relevant details & submit To understand the detailed procedure, visit here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is trade history summary report?",
    "answer": "Trade history report contains details about all your transactions and corresponding charges with other information such as date, type, and segment of order."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I download the trade history summary report?",
    "answer": "You can download the trade summary report from our app. Follow the steps below. Go to the Account section on the App. Go to Trades and charges Click on Download trade history"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Ledger Statement?",
    "answer": "Ledger is a record of your account transactions, updated daily. It contains details of fund pay-ins and fund withdrawals, payments made for purchases, payments received for sell transactions, and charges incurred. It also gives a running balance of the cash limit in your account. For details on how to read ledger “ Click Here “"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I download Ledger statements?",
    "answer": "You can download your ledger statement by following these steps. Login to your Angel One account. Go to the Account section in the application. You will find the Statements/Ledger section on this screen. Click on it. Select the time period. Click on the download button on the top right part of the screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my funds pay-in be reflected in my ledger?",
    "answer": "Reflection of funds in your account varies with the payment partner / option selected by you – Upto 5 minutes – UPI Payments / Google Pay Upto 15-30 minutes – Net Banking Upto 3 hours – NEFT / RTGS"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my ledger be udpated with my trading transactions?",
    "answer": "Your Ledger will be updated with your trading transaction by the end of the trading day."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will Funds reflect in my Demat account?",
    "answer": "Reflection of funds in your account varies with the payment partner / option selected by you – UPI Payments / Google Pay – Instantly Net Banking – Instantly NEFT / RTGS – 3-4 Hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I get money in my bank account after placing a fund withdrawal request?",
    "answer": "We process your fund withdrawal request as per the below timeline: Days Payout Request Time Funds Credited By (approx) Monday to Friday 12:00 am – 07:00 am 11:30 am, Same Day 07:00 am – 05:30 pm 11:30 pm, Same Day 05:30 pm – 12:00 am 11:30 am, Next Working Day Saturday, Sunday Anytime 11:30 am, Next Working Day Trading/Settlement Holiday Anytime 11:30 am, Next Working Day To learn more about the fund withdrawal cycle, click here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I withdraw funds after selling my shares?",
    "answer": "You can withdraw money from your sell transaction on T+1 day, except for Saturday, Sunday, and Trading/Settlement holidays. For example, if you sold your shares on 14th August, the amount from the transaction will be available for withdrawal on 16th August, since 15th August is a trading holiday. Click here for more information."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawal amount not credited to my bank on time?",
    "answer": "The delay in crediting your withdrawal amount can be due to the following reasons: Bank Delay: Angel One has approved your request, but there’s a delay at the bank’s end. Please wait for 4 hours or directly contact your bank in this case. New Trades: If you entered into new trades after placing the withdrawal request, it can delay the settlement and processing. Please wait for 24 hours for processing and approval. Non-Trading Days: Withdrawal requests are processed only on trading/working days. For example, if you placed a request at 6 pm on Thursday, and Friday and the next Monday are holidays, your funds will be credited by 11:30 am on Tuesday. Consider weekends and trading/settlement holidays when planning your withdrawal. High Volume of Requests: In rare cases, a high number of requests can delay processing from Angel One. Please wait for 6 hours from the cut-off time and reach out for support."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawable balance different from the available trading balance?",
    "answer": "The difference between your withdrawable and trading balance could be due to the following reasons. When you enter a trade, your trading balance changes in real-time but the withdrawable balance is updated at the end of the day. Funds from sell transactions can be withdrawn on T+1 day (the next working day). You cannot withdraw funds on the same day you added them; you can withdraw them on the next working day. Click here to get more detailed information on the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my money not credited to my bank account even though the withdrawal request is approved?",
    "answer": "If your withdrawal request is approved, it indicates that Angel One has instructed your bank to credit the amount. Please wait till the expected time mentioned on the app. If the time has passed, please wait for 5-6 hours. You can also check your bank statement and contact your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawal amount not credited instantly?",
    "answer": "Withdrawal requests are not credited instantly because they are processed in batches to account for any trades you might have entered on that day. These requests are processed after trading hours, considering your buy/sell transactions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawal request partially approved?",
    "answer": "Your withdrawal request might be partially approved due to the following reasons: New Trades: You entered into new trades after placing the request. Example: If you had Rs. 1000 and placed a withdrawal request at 11 am for Rs. 1000, but then bought shares worth Rs. 500 at 2 pm, you will receive Rs. 500 (minus brokerage and charges). Margin Requirements: You have margin requirements in your account. Accrual Charges: You have pending accrual charges on your account. Click here for more information."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check the status of my fund withdrawal request?",
    "answer": "You can follow these steps to check the status of your withdrawal request: Click on the Account screen in the app. Scroll down to the Dash section. Click on Fund Transactions . Click on Funds Withdrawn . Click here to find all the fund withdrawal requests and their statuses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to withdraw my money from my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to withdraw your money for the following reasons: Sell Transactions: Funds from sell transactions can be withdrawn on T+1 day (the next working day). For example, if you sold shares worth Rs. 1000 on Friday, you can place a withdrawal request on Monday. Same-Day Deposits: Funds added to your account cannot be withdrawn on the same day; you can withdraw them on the next working day."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I withdraw funds from my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can withdraw your funds from the Angel One account by following the below steps. Log in to your account. Go to the Account screen. Click on the “ Withdraw ”  button under Trading Balance at the top of the screen. Here you will be able to check the withdrawable amount . You can enter the amount you want to withdraw and the bank account to which the money needs to be credited. Please note the estimated credit time shown on the screen. Kindly note that the withdrawal amount is updated every morning after taking the previous day’s transactions into account."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawable balance less than the trading balance?",
    "answer": "Your withdrawable balance is the amount eligible for withdrawal on a given day. Any unsettled balance from your trades will be available for withdrawal on T+1 day (next working day). The following balances will be available for withdrawal on the next working day: Funds from delivery sell transactions. Profits from intraday transactions. Profits from F&O transactions. Funds from commodity and currency transactions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my withdrawable balance not updated?",
    "answer": "Your withdrawable balance is updated once every morning, after adjusting for all the transactions made on the previous trading day. This balance can be different from the trading balance, which changes in real time."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a payout account?",
    "answer": "A payout account is where your fixed deposit investments will be credited upon maturity. This is the account where you will receive your money back."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add someone else's bank account details?",
    "answer": "No, the payout account should belong to you. We do not allow the use of another person’s account for payout. Please use an account that is in your name."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I add my bank if it is not in the list?",
    "answer": "Click on the Search tab, enter your bank name, and you will be able to select your bank to add as the payout account for your fixed deposit."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if my bank is inactive but my bank details are correct?",
    "answer": "Your payout account must be an active bank account for us to credit the money on maturity or withdrawal. If your bank status is inactive, either add another active bank account or check with your bank regarding your account status."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did I receive an SMS of INR 1 credit?",
    "answer": "We verify your bank account by transferring INR 1. This verification process might result in an SMS from your bank informing you about the credit."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if the bank servers are down?",
    "answer": "Retry after some time or use a different bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if my payment fails?",
    "answer": "If your payment fails and the amount is deducted, it will be refunded within 2-4 working days. You can place another request for an FD if you are still interested."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did my payment fail?",
    "answer": "Third-party limit error: Check your daily online transaction limit in your net banking, as exceeding this limit will cause the transaction to fail. UPI limit error: UPI transactions have a daily limit of Rs 1 lakh. Ensure you are not exceeding this limit. Bank connection error: Sometimes the connection to your bank’s page or UPI app page may break during payment, causing the transaction to fail."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I haven't received the refund yet?",
    "answer": "Your money is safe. If you haven’t received the refund within 7 working days, check your bank account statement for refund transactions and ensure 7 working days have passed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I am stuck on the payment step and cannot understand the current status?",
    "answer": "Click on “Go to Dashboard” to track your FDs in the Pending Investments tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "What interest rate will I get in case of a premature withdrawal?",
    "answer": "For premature withdrawal, the interest rate applicable will be for the tenure the FD was maintained. A penalty rate will also apply, and the net off penalty rate will be the applicable interest rate."
  },
  {
    "question": "When and where will I receive my money in case of a withdrawal?",
    "answer": "You will receive your money within 2 working days after successfully placing withdrawal instructions to the account details provided during the FD booking process."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any withdrawal processing charges?",
    "answer": "No, there are no withdrawal processing charges."
  },
  {
    "question": "How will I know when my withdrawal is completed?",
    "answer": "You will receive an SMS or notification from the bank regarding the crediting of money in your account. The FD booking will be automatically removed post-withdrawal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I prematurely withdraw my FD?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can prematurely withdraw your Fixed Deposit with Axis Bank and Utkarsh Bank once the lock-in period is completed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my trading balance not updated even after adding funds successfully?",
    "answer": "If your trading balance is not updated after a successful fund addition, it could be due to the following reasons: High Volume of Requests : When there is a high volume of fund addition requests, it might take some time to update your balance. Please wait for 15 minutes. Bank Account Issues : Ensure you add funds from the bank account registered with Angel One, and the account should be in your name. If funds are added from an unregistered bank account, the amount might get deducted but will be credited back in 3-4 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds to your Angel One account due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You might be trying to add funds from a bank account not registered with your Angel One account. Incorrect UPI ID : The UPI ID used for fund addition might not be mapped to the bank account registered with Angel One. Ensure you add funds from your bank account registered with Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds using UPI?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds via UPI due to the following reasons: Bank Account Mismatch : The bank account linked with Angel One is different from the one selected in the UPI app. Unregistered UPI ID : Your UPI ID is mapped to a bank account that is not registered with Angel One. Timeout : Your UPI request on the app was not accepted within 10 minutes. Transfer Limit Exceeded : Your UPI transfer limit set by your bank is exhausted. Daily Limit Reached : Your daily UPI transaction limit is reached across all UPI apps. Insufficient Balance : You may have an insufficient balance in your bank account. Network Issues : Network failure at the bank’s/provider’s system. Incorrect UPI ID : Your UPI ID (VPA) entered is incorrect. Wrong UPI PIN : You have entered the wrong UPI PIN. Incorrect Method : You are transferring funds to Angel One’s UPI ID directly instead of using the ‘Add Funds’ option on the Angel One app/platform. Ensure you follow the correct procedure and check the above points to resolve the issue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to add funds using net banking?",
    "answer": "You might be unable to add funds via net banking due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You are making payments from a bank account that is not registered with Angel One. Mismatched Bank Details : You have added different bank account details on the ‘Add Funds’ page and net banking page. Incorrect Credentials : You have entered incorrect credentials on the bank’s net banking page. Insufficient Balance : You have insufficient balance in your bank account to make the transaction. Transaction Limits : Your bank has placed limits on your transaction amount or the number of transactions. Network Failure : There may be a network failure at the bank’s or provider’s system. Ensure you check these points and follow the correct procedure to add funds via net banking."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the different options available to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can add funds using any of the following options. Add funds using payment apps such as PhonePe, Google Pay, etc. Add funds using UPI ID. Add funds using net banking. Please make sure to add funds from your bank account registered with Angel One in all the above options."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I add funds from any bank account to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "No, you can add funds only from your bank account registered with Angel One. This is in accordance with SEBI guidelines. You cannot add funds from a bank account that belongs to your spouse, friend, or anyone else."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You can add funds online to your Angel One account by following these steps: Tap on Account at the bottom of your screen. Click on Add Funds . Enter the amount and choose the mode of transfer (Google Pay, PhonePe, other UPI methods, or Net banking). Follow the subsequent steps to authorize your transaction, and the funds will be added to your account. Click here for more details on adding funds."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it mandatory to add funds via bank account registered with Angel One?",
    "answer": "Yes, as per regulatory guidelines and compliance norms, it is mandatory to transfer funds through the bank accounts registered with Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my amount debited from bank but not added to my trading balance?",
    "answer": "If the amount is debited from the bank but not added to your Angel One balance, it could be due to the following reasons: Unregistered Bank Account : You might have tried to add funds from an unregistered bank account. The debited amount will be credited back to your bank in 3-4 working days. Technical Glitch : There could be a technical glitch at your bank’s end. The debited amount will be refunded in 3-4 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use debit/credit card to add funds to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "You cannot add funds to your Angel One account using your debit or credit card. As per the regulatory guidelines, your transactions should be from a verified bank account. Also, the usage of credit cards is not allowed in the stock markets."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there a limit on the amount of funds that I can add to my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "The limit for fund addition via UPI is 1 lakh per day. For net banking, the limit will be applicable as per the bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a surveillance measure?",
    "answer": "Market surveillance plays a key role in ensuring safety and integrity of the markets as it the process of prevention and investigation of abusive, manipulative or illegal trading practices in the securities markets. Surveillance Measure is an initative by the regulatory bodies and exchanges to protect traders and investors by monitoring price and volatility and detecting misleading activities like insider trading, fictitious transactions, and more."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ASM?",
    "answer": "SEBI (Securities and Exchange Board of India) along with the stock exchanges have initiated an Additional Surveillance Measure or ASM to safeguard investors’ interests by ensuring there are no market speculations or manipulations like unexpected price movements. The stocks are categorized under ASM for surveillance based on criteria specified by NSE here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is GSM?",
    "answer": "GSM or Graded Surveillance Measure is a system used by Indian Stock Exchanges like NSE and BSE to alert traders/investors and ask them to be extra cautious while dealing in certain securities which have been categorized under GSM. Scrips can be classified under GSM due to abnormal price hike that doesn’t match with the company’s financial health, are illiquid, have negligible market capital, and are underpreforming."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between ASM and GSM?",
    "answer": "The main aim of the ASM framework is to control stock volatility, while the primary objective of GSM is to protect the investors from underperforming stocks by not allowing intraday trading and to advise them to be extra vigilant while dealing with securities that are witnessing unusual price fluctuations. Both these frameworks are introduced with different objectives, but their main goal is to protect traders and investors."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the basis of categorizing a scrip under ASM?",
    "answer": "SEBI and Exchanges jointly decides the objective criterion to shortlist securities under ASM based on the following parameters: 1. High Low Variation 2. Client Concentration 3. Close to Close Price Variation 4. Market Capitalization 5. Volume Variation 6. Delivery Percentage 7. No. of Unique PANs & PEs"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will a scrip be classified under GSM?",
    "answer": "On the basis of below-mentioned pointers, Regulatory Body and the Exchanges make their decision of adding a scrip under GSM category: 1. Periodic Call Auction Session for Illiquid Securities 2. Periodic Review of Movement of Securities to/from Trade for Trade 3. Persistent Noise Creators 4. Rumour Verification and Clarification in case of Spurt in Price/Volume"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will a scrip get out of ASM/GSM?",
    "answer": "Every 2 months in the case of ASM and every quarter in the case of GSM, the stock can go in and out of the list based on the review carried out by the exchange."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the surveillance measures under ASM?",
    "answer": "Please find the detailed surveillance measures under ASM here ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why were my funds withdrawn and credited to my bank account even though I didn’t place a request?",
    "answer": "There are two reasons why this could happen. Quarterly Settlement: As per the SEBI guidelines, all stockbrokers are required to transfer the funds lying in the client account back to their bank at least once every quarter. The funds will be transferred back to the primary bank account mapped to your Angel One account. Fund Settlement Frequency: Your fund settlement frequency might be set to daily settlement. You can edit it by visiting Account → Profile → Fund Settlement Frequency in our mobile app."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is quarterly settlement of funds or SEBI payout?",
    "answer": "The quarterly settlement of funds is a SEBI requirement for all stockbrokers to settle client funds lying in trading accounts at least once every quarter. The funds are transferred back to the primary bank account mapped to your Angel One account."
  },
  {
    "question": "My chart is not loading and showing \"Something went wrong\". What should I do?",
    "answer": "Open Playstore Search for Google Chrome on Playstore Update Google Chrome or your default browser to the latest version The chart should load successfully now If the chart loading fails & issue still exists : Open Playstore again Search for Android System Webview Click to Update the Android System Webview to the latest version"
  },
  {
    "question": "My Chart view is not loading in Angel One web app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Go to settings -> privacy and security -> clear browser history."
  },
  {
    "question": "My Chart view is not loading in Angel One mobile app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Open application settings and clear cache and clear data, once cleared, chart should load."
  },
  {
    "question": "Price is not updating realtime on charts on the Angel one web app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Always check system timezone is in sync with your chart timestamp. Also device timezone is synced with IST."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I am living in other timezones from India and my chart is not updating real time or candles are not forming improperly?",
    "answer": "If the charts are not working correctly in other timezones , try to come in Indian timezone and check the functioning of charts. Our team is working to give a more flexible and permanent fix for this."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are transaction/turnover charges?",
    "answer": "Transaction/Turnover charges are charges that are levied by the Exchange on the turnover from every trader to provide them with the technology platform to buy & sell securities. Click here to check the details on transaction charges."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Basket Order?",
    "answer": "Basket Order is a feature that allows you to place multiple orders at the same time in a single click."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which segments are allowed within the basket?",
    "answer": "All the market segments, such as Equity (Cash and F&O), Index, Currency, and Commodity are allowed within the basket."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which order types are allowed within the basket?",
    "answer": "Order types available within the basket are: Limit Order and Market Order Delivery, Margin, Carryforward, and Intraday Advanced Orders – Stop Loss, Cover, and Robo Order Note – Please note that GTT orders cannot be placed inside the basket."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many baskets can be created?",
    "answer": "A maximum of 50 baskets can be created and saved. Also, within each basket, a maximum of 20 securities can be added."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any charge for placing a Basket Order?",
    "answer": "No, there is no additional charge for placing a Basket Order. You just have to pay the existing brokerage for the orders in the basket."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any specific time to place a Basket Order?",
    "answer": "Basket Orders can be placed only within the market hours i.e., between 9:15 am and 3:15 pm. However, you can create and save the basket anytime during the day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I clone my basket?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can clone your existing baskets. Additionally, you can also clone any order inside the basket."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to check the required margin for placing the Basket Order?",
    "answer": "The required margin and the available margin will be shown upfront in the Basket. To give you the margin benefit, the required margin for the entire basket will be calculated using the SPAN calculator."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if the available margin is less than the required margin?",
    "answer": "You can add the funds with the ‘Add Funds’ feature within the Basket to match the required margin."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will happen to my basket after execution?",
    "answer": "After placing the Basket Order, the status of individual orders will be shown inside the basket. You can take decisions at the individual order level like modifying a pending order or retrying a failed order."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I see my placed Basket Order the next day?",
    "answer": "If you have saved your basket, then you can see it the next day, but the orders will be reset to the initial state i.e., before placing the Basket Order. However, you won’t be able to see the status of the orders. Please know that if you don’t manually save the basket, it will not appear in the Baskets Tab."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the margin benefit in the Basket?",
    "answer": "When you place individual orders, you do not get a hedging benefit and have to pay the entire required margin upfront. But when you hedge your position in the basket (i.e. combine 2 or more orders), you get the benefit of hedging in terms of lower required margin."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can the basket save time in order execution?",
    "answer": "You can save time using Basket Order as multiple orders are placed in one click. So, there is no need to place and execute individual orders."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to interpret Boring and Explosive Indicators?",
    "answer": "Absolute (OpenPrice – ClosePrice) / Absolute (HighPrice – LowPrice) < 0.5, Colour it as Boring Candle Absolute (OpenPrice – ClosePrice) / Absolute (HighPrice – LowPrice) > 0.5, Colour it as Explosive Candle If the value = 0.5 , do not change the candle colour"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to interpret ORB Indicator?",
    "answer": "Opening Range Breakout – Opening Range is high and low price range of the 1st candle in Intraday period specified. Any Following candle after that first candle breaking the upper range is Buy Signal and breaking the lower range is Sell signal."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to interpret settings for Bollinger Bands?",
    "answer": "Bollinger Bands are a technical analysis tool used by traders and investors to help interpret and analyze price volatility and potential price reversals in financial markets. You can check out how to interpret Bollinger Bands in this article ."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I book another FD if I already have one running?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can invest in multiple Fixed Deposits (FDs) with different providers. You can also have multiple FDs with the same provider."
  },
  {
    "question": "What additional benefits can I avail as a senior citizen?",
    "answer": "Most banks and NBFCs offer an additional interest rate of up to 0.5% over the regular fixed deposit interest rates for senior citizens, making it even more attractive for you."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I book an FD as an NRI?",
    "answer": "Currently, we are not able to process fixed deposit requests for NRIs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I book an FD as a minor?",
    "answer": "Currently, we are not able to process fixed deposit requests for minors."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are recommendations?",
    "answer": "Recommendations are stocks suggested by Angel One to help you minimize risk and maximize profit. You can see the recommendations by visiting https://www.angelone.in/trade/home You will find the recommendations under “Top Stock Picks via Advisory” section on this screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for recommendations?",
    "answer": "We don’t charge any fee for recommendations. The usual trading charges will be levied when a user takes a trade."
  },
  {
    "question": "Recommend me some best growing stocks?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can also explore the Portfolio advisory on the home screen if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Suggest me some stocks for short term or intraday?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can explore the Portfolio advisory if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Suggest me stocks for long term investment?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can explore the Portfolio advisory if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check my Order Status?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen Click on Open Orders to see all your Pending Orders You will be able to see your Executed Orders by clicking on the Position You can also view complete list of orders by clicking order history button under open orders"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I know if my order has been completed?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen You will be able to see your executed/completed Orders by clicking on the Positions options You can also see your past orders by clicking order history button under open orders tab"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check today's positions?",
    "answer": "Tap on Orders at the bottom of your screen You will be able to see your current existing Positions by clicking on the Positions tab You can also view your closed positions by clicking on “View Closed Positions” tab"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my Order pending?",
    "answer": "Orders can be pending due to reasons like changes in market price, order price is not reached or there are low number of buyers/sellers."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Call & Trade Charges?",
    "answer": "Call & Trade charges are applicable if the transaction is done over a phone call. Charges for Call & Trade are Rs 20+GST per executed Order. They are levied only after the execution of a trade."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Client Master List?",
    "answer": "Client Master List (CML) is a document with details of your DEMAT account providing your information such as name, address, DOB, bank account, nominations etc. To know about Client Master List “ Click Here “"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I get a copy of my Client Master List (CML)?",
    "answer": "While we dont have reports yet. We are working on it to make it avaible to you ASAP. You can follow our product updated on our blog."
  },
  {
    "question": "How come I need to purchase the contracts after the stock options expire?",
    "answer": "If your stock options contract expire in ITM (Profit), you will have to purchase your contracts. As a result, if you are not interested in purchasing the contracts and only interested in trading them, it is recommended that you sell them before they expire."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any Angel One desktop application for trading?",
    "answer": "We currently do not have a desktop application for trading. We have optimized our web platform to meet the trading needs. Do let us know if you are looking for any specific improvements."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I use sensibull on Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can access Sensibull from the Home screen of mobile or web platform. On the home page, scroll down to find External services. Here you will find an option to navigate to Smallcase, Sensibull, Streak etc. Also, please note that Sensibull is free for Angel One customers."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I trade or invest in US stocks with Angel One?",
    "answer": "We have partnered with Vested, a platfor that allows investing in US stock market. You can Vested on the Angel One home page. Scroll down to find External services. Here you will find an option to navigate to Vested. Completely your KYC with Vested to start investing in US stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there any Angel One app for PC?",
    "answer": "We currently do not have a desktop application for trading. We have optimized our web platform to meet the trading needs. Do let us know if you are looking for any specific improvements."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Margin Trading Facility (MTF)?",
    "answer": "Margin Trading Facility (MTF) allows an investor to buy a stock by paying just a fraction of the total transaction value. The balance amount is funded by the broker. As an illustration Your Account Balance = Rs. 25,000 MTF gives you upto 4x buying power = Rs 100,000 (25,000 x 4) Thus, your enhanced Buying Capacity is now = Rs. 125,000."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Margin required?",
    "answer": "Margin required is the amount you need to pay initially to buy stocks under margin products. Margin amount can be paid either in the form of Cash, or by pledging your holdings (margin pledge)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the margin is less?",
    "answer": "In order to buy stocks under Margin Trading Facility, you need to fulfil the Minimum Margin requirement. If your margin is less than that, then you will have to add funds to proceed with your transaction."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the interest rate charged for using MTF?",
    "answer": "A standard interest rate of 0.041% per day (14.97% per annum) is charged on the borrowed amount."
  },
  {
    "question": "How long can I hold the stocks purchased via MTF?",
    "answer": "In case you have pledged the shares, you can hold them as long as you want unless you either sell your Pay Later (MTF) positions or convert them to delivery by adding funds."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I start incurring interest charges?",
    "answer": "Interest is levied from the 2nd day onwards after you placed an MTF trade, till the outstanding amount is cleared, and/or your position is squared-off."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is MTF Pledge?",
    "answer": "As per SEBI guidelines, your shares bought using PayLater (MTF) will be automatically pledged . There is no action needed from your end"
  },
  {
    "question": "When would my shares purchased under MTF be squared-off?",
    "answer": "For shares purchased under MTF, square-off will be triggered in either of the below scenarios: If there is a margin shortfall, shares will be squared-off 4 trading days after the shortfall has occurred."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Pledging/Un-pledging shares under MTF?",
    "answer": "When you raise a request to Pledge or Unpledge your shares, charge of Rs 20/- plus GST is levied per scrip."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is MTF Pledge different from Margin Pledge?",
    "answer": "Margin Pledge means using your existing holdings / portfolio to get additional limit / margin. You can then use this additional margin for Equity Intraday, futures & options writing (equity and currency F&O). As per SEBI guidelines, shares bought under MTF have to be compulsorily pledged. This is called MTF pledge. Unlike Margin Pledge, you do not get additional limit against these shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can Margin Trading Facility be used for trading in Futures & Options, Currency, or Commodity segment?",
    "answer": "No. MTF Facility is applicable for trading in equity shares only."
  },
  {
    "question": "I do not want to use Margin Facility. What should I do?",
    "answer": "If you do not wish to use Margin facility you can place orders using Delivery product type. Kindly make sure that you have adequate funds before placing your Order. Kindly check your available funds in the Account -> Trading Balance Summary"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate MTF or Pay later on the Angel One app?",
    "answer": "You can activate MTF or Pay later by visiting the Profile page on the Angel One app. Alternatively, you can navigate to Account → Profile → MTF to activate MTF for your account. You will have to enter the Aadhar number and verify the OTP. Once the request is submitted, it will take up to 2 working days to activate MTF for your account."
  },
  {
    "question": "My chart is not loading and showing \"Something went wrong\". What should I do?",
    "answer": "Open Playstore Search for Google Chrome on Playstore Update Google Chrome or your default browser to the latest version The chart should load successfully now If the chart loading fails & issue still exists : Open Playstore again Search for Android System Webview Click to Update the Android System Webview to the latest version"
  },
  {
    "question": "My Chart view is not loading in Angel One web app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Go to settings -> privacy and security -> clear browser history."
  },
  {
    "question": "My Chart view is not loading in Angel One mobile app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Open application settings and clear cache and clear data, once cleared, chart should load."
  },
  {
    "question": "Price is not updating realtime on charts on the Angel one web app. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Always check system timezone is in sync with your chart timestamp. Also device timezone is synced with IST."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I am living in other timezones from India and my chart is not updating real time or candles are not forming improperly?",
    "answer": "If the charts are not working correctly in other timezones , try to come in Indian timezone and check the functioning of charts. Our team is working to give a more flexible and permanent fix for this."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is TPIN?",
    "answer": "TPIN stands for Transaction Personal Identification Number. CDSL has introduced TPIN, which will enable investors to authorise selling securities from their demat accounts virtually. For Non POA clients, TPIN verification will be valid for 1 day. Once you generate TPIN, it will be valid till you generate it again. Hence, please make a note of your TPIN for quicker verification. An OTP will also be required apart from TPIN for selling shares from demat account."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I generate TPIN?",
    "answer": "Follow the below steps to generate a new TPIN. Go to Portfolio section on the App. Click on Verify to Sell. You will be redirected to CDSL website. Now you can either enter the existing TPIN or click on the option to generate TPIN. If you choose to generate TPIN, you will need to enter BO ID and PAN details. You can find your BO ID in Account → Profile section of the App (Also called as DP ID). Once you enter BO ID & PAN and then OTP, your TPIN will be sent to your mobile number and email ID. Please make a note of your TPIN so that you can reuse it later."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I sell stocks without TPIN verification?",
    "answer": "You will have to activate DDPI in order to sell stocks without TPIN verification. For entire process to activate DDPI, click here . You can check your DDPI status on our platform by visiting Account → Profile → View All Categories (under personal details)."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much time does it take to activate the account after KYC completion?",
    "answer": "Once your KYC documents are submitted, it may take up to 3 working days to activate your account. You will receive your client ID on the registered email address."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I receive my user ID and password after submitting my KYC application?",
    "answer": "You will receive your user ID, also called as client ID within 3 working days. You can use the client ID to login to the Angel One app. Password is not required to login to your account. You will have to set up an MPIN while logging in for the first time."
  },
  {
    "question": "What can I do if my KYC application is rejected?",
    "answer": "Technically, your application is not rejected. It will be kept on hold if there’s some issue with the application. The issue could be one of the below. Signature validation issue PAN validation issue Selfie validation issue Name mismatch issue Address proof validation issue Bank details validation issue In case of the above issues, you will receive a link via email and SMS to re-upload the required documents. Please wait for 1 working day . If you didn’t receive any communication from Angel One, please wait for 2 working days. Our sales team will get in touch with you ."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to check the status of my account opening application?",
    "answer": "You can check the status of your application by logging into your Angel One account. Open the Angel One app → Enter the mobile number/client code → Verify the OTP. You will be able to see the application status on the home page of the app. You will receive your user ID or client code in your email once the application is verified and approved by Angel One. You can also try to see if there is something to be done from your side by logging in here . If there is no action to be taken, kindly wait for 2 working days for our team to set up your account. For more details please refer to this article ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Off-MKT transactions charges?",
    "answer": "Off-MKT transactions charges are applicable when you transfer shares from one demat account to another"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for Off-MKT transactions?",
    "answer": "Off-MKT transactions are a flat transaction fee of Rs 20 (+GST). This fee is charged per scrip and notas per volume. Hence, they remain the same whether you transfer 1 share or 100 shares."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the duration of Off-MKT charges?",
    "answer": "Off-MKT charges are charged on a daily basis whenever you transfer any scrip from your demat account to another demat account."
  },
  {
    "question": "My monthly instalment for SIPs are not getting debited?",
    "answer": "Your Monthly instalments for SIPs will get debited automatically on SIP day only if your SIPs are linked to an autopay. If you have not setup an autopay, your instalments will not be paid. To setup and manage autopay, Please click on the link below Manage Autopay"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does my monthly instalment for SIPs get paid automatically?",
    "answer": "Your monthly instalments for SIPs get paid automatically if you have set up Autopay and linked your SIP to an autopay. If you have not setup an autopay, your instalments will not be paid. This is one time process. Once you setup an autopay, all your current and future SIPs will be linked to that autopay."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my instalment order in progress if SIP date is yet to come?",
    "answer": "We generally create your SIP installment order 2/3 working days before your due date as we have to co-ordinate with your Auto-pay linked bank account well in advance to ensure your SIP instalments goes through smoothly on due date. Order Date is when we create your SIP instalment order in our system and SIP due date is when money will be debited from your Autopay linked bank account. NAV applicable is usually of your SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to link my SIP to an autopay?",
    "answer": "To check if any particular SIP is linked to an Autopay. Please click on the particular you want to link. On top, you will see a ‘Link Autopay’ button if your SIP is not linked to autopay."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will happen if I do not have sufficient balance in my bank account on SIP due date?",
    "answer": "Your SIP instalment will fail if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your autopay linked bank account. Your bank can also charge you if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your bank account on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Money got deducted from my bank account but payment status shows payment in progress?",
    "answer": "We have not received confirmation of successful payment from your bank account. We will update the status as soon as possible. Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will SIP amount get debited from my bank account for my Active SIPs?",
    "answer": "Your money will get debited automatically only if your SIP is linked to an autopay. If your SIP is linked to an autopay. SIP amount will get debited on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for pledging of shares?",
    "answer": "Pledging of shares is charged a flat transaction fee, irrespective of the quantity pledged. A fixed transaction fee of ₹20 + GST is charged for each pledge and unpledge request, regardless of the number of shares. The split is as follows. INR 5 (Depository) + INR 15 (Angel One Charge) + GST"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is family declaration?",
    "answer": "As per regulatory requirement, every KYC account should have a separate and unique mobile number and email address . In case if account holder wishes to use common email Id/ Mobile number for more than one account of family, it can be done after submitting a written declaration giving required details and duly signed by people involved."
  },
  {
    "question": "What relationships are permitted as per SEBI to be considered as family for this purpose?",
    "answer": "Family for this purpose has been defined by SEBI as self, spouse, dependent parents and dependent children (in case of individual account holders)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What relationship can be given for clients having no- individual category of account such as company, trust, HUF, AOP etc.",
    "answer": "In case of non-individual category of account, if common email id/mobile number is used for more than one account then relationship can be defined as “Authorised Signatory” and the supporting needs to be submitted along with declaration such as Board resolution copy, trust/partnership deed or other such officially valid document approved giving detalils of authorized persons."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are siblings or other relationships such as daughter-in-law, son-in-law allowed for considering family for this purpose?",
    "answer": "No. Only SEBI defined relationships of self, spouse, dependent parents and dependent children are allowed to be considered as family for this purpose. Anything else apart from this is not allowed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if the client is found to be using the common email id/mobile number without allowable relationship?",
    "answer": "Such account will be considered as invalid KYC accounts and will be suspended in both trading and demat account till the time unique valid KYC credentials are updated."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the client change their email ID and/or Mobile number to avoid non-compliance?",
    "answer": "Modification request can be submitted to change the mobile number/email ID by submitting request from the profile page of client’s account login."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can a client find the Family Declaration Form?",
    "answer": "Client can download the Family Declaration Form from here . Send the duly signed scan copy on support@angelbroking.com .  Hard copy of declaration can be sent at below mentioned address. Angel One Limited. 5th Floor Akruti Star Andheri (E) Mumbai- 400 093"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who needs to sign the Family Declaration Form?",
    "answer": "The client who wants to use common email Id/ Mobile number, will mention the demat and trading account details and sign at the bottom of the page. If the demat account has more than one holder, all the holders will sign at respective place. The person who is Sellf (whose email id /mobile number is used will sign at the place “Signature of the related person”."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Holding statements?",
    "answer": "The holding statement provides all the details of your portfolio/holdings at any given time. You will find the stock names, average price, quantity, and other details in the holding statement."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I download Holding statements?",
    "answer": "You can download your holding statements in an Excel sheet by following these steps. Login to your Angel One account. Go to the Portfolio section on the App. Choose Equity, Mutual Funds, SGB, etc. Click on the download button on the top right part of the screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my portfolio be updated with my latest investments?",
    "answer": "Your portfolio will be updated with your latest investments on an immediate basis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Sovereign Gold Bond (SGB) & who is the issuer?",
    "answer": "SGBs are government securities denominated in grams of gold. They are an alternate to holding physical gold. SGBs are issued by RBI on behalf of the Government of India."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why should I buy SGB rather than physical gold & what are the benefits?",
    "answer": "SGBs offer investors with a range of benefits, such as The quantity of gold for which the investor pays is protected, since he receives the ongoing market price at the time of redemption/ premature redemption. No risks and costs of physical storage. No making charges and purity issues Earn interest at 2.5% per year on the initial investment.& Interest is credited twice a year."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are there any risks in investing in SGBs?",
    "answer": "There may be a risk of capital loss if the market price of gold declines. However, the investor does not lose in terms of the units of gold that he/she has paid for."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is eligible to invest in the SGBs?",
    "answer": "All Indian residents as defined under Foreign Exchange Management Act, of 1999 are eligible to invest in SGBs. Eligible investors include individuals, HUFs, trusts, universities and charitable institutions."
  },
  {
    "question": "Whether joint holding will be allowed?",
    "answer": "Yes, joint holding is allowed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a Minor invest in SGB?",
    "answer": "Yes. The application on behalf of the minor has to be made by his/her guardian."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum and maximum limit for investment?",
    "answer": "The Bonds are issued in denominations of one gram of gold and in multiples thereof. Minimum investment in the Bond shall be one gram with a maximum limit of subscription of 4 kg for individuals, 4 kg for Hindu Undivided Family (HUF) and 20 kg for trusts and similar entities notified by the government from time to time per fiscal year (April-March). In case of joint holding, the limit applies to the first applicant. The annual ceiling will include bonds subscribed under different tranches during initial issuance by Government and those purchased from the secondary market. The ceiling on investment will not include the holdings as collateral by banks and other Financial Institutions."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the rate of interest and how will the interest be paid?",
    "answer": "The Bonds bear interest at the rate of 2.50% (fixed rate) per annum on the amount of initial investment. Interest will be credited semi-annually to the bank account of the investor and the last interest will be payable on maturity along with the principal. There will be no capital gain tax at maturity."
  },
  {
    "question": "At what price the bonds are sold?",
    "answer": "The nominal value of Gold Bonds shall be in Indian Rupees fixed on the basis of simple average of closing price of gold of 999 purity, published by the India Bullion and Jewelers Association Limited, for the last 3 business days of the week preceding the subscription period."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will RBI publish the rate of gold applicable every day?",
    "answer": "The price of gold for the relevant tranche will be published on the RBI website two days before the issue opens."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will I get on redemption?",
    "answer": "On maturity, the Gold Bonds shall be redeemed in Indian Rupees and the redemption price shall be based on simple average of closing price of gold of 999 purity of previous 3 business days from the date of repayment, published by the India Bullion and Jewelers Association Limited."
  },
  {
    "question": "How will I get the redemption amount?",
    "answer": "Interest and redemption proceeds will be credited to the bank account furnished by the customer at the time of buying the bond."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the procedures involved during redemption?",
    "answer": "The investor will be advised one month before maturity regarding the ensuing maturity of the bond. On the date of maturity, the maturity proceeds will be credited to the registered bank account."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I encash the bond anytime I want? Is premature redemption allowed?",
    "answer": "Though the tenor of the bond is 8 years, early encashment/redemption of the bond is allowed after the fifth year from the date of issue. The bond can be traded on Exchanges, if held in demat form. It can also be transferred to any other eligible investor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I gift the bonds to a relative or friend on some occasion?",
    "answer": "The bond can be gifted/transferred to a relative/friend/anybody who fulfills the eligibility criteria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is tax deducted at source (TDS) applicable on the bond?",
    "answer": "TDS is not applicable to the bond. However, it is the responsibility of the bond holder to comply with the tax laws."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I trade these bonds?",
    "answer": "The bonds are tradable from a date to be notified by RBI. (It may be noted that only bonds held in demat form with depositories can be traded on stock exchanges) The bonds can also be sold and transferred as per provisions of Government Securities Act, 2006. Partial transfer of bonds is also possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I find my UPI ID?",
    "answer": "Generally, you can find your UPI ID in the profile section of the respective app you are using."
  },
  {
    "question": "I don’t have a UPI ID. Can I apply for an IPO?",
    "answer": "In case you don’t have a UPI ID, you can create it with any of the UPI Handles featured in the NPCI list. Alternatively, you can apply through ASBA with your bank or through physical form."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I create my UPI ID?",
    "answer": "You can follow the below steps to create a UPI ID with the BHIM app Download the Google Pay/ PhonePe / BHIM App Verify your mobile number Register the passcode (it is required to open the app) Select your bank from the options available The app will fetch your bank details In case you have more than one account, choose the account you want to register with BHIM Set up a UPI PIN for security Now you can check your UPI ID in the profile section."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to apply for IPOs via my UPI ID/Handle?",
    "answer": "For IPO applications, only UPI ID/Handles approved by NPCI are allowed. In case you are unable to apply for IPO using your UPI ID/Handle, we recommend that you check the list of banks/apps approved by NPCI for providing UPI service for IPO application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can’t I see my UPI handle listed in the dropdown in the Angel One app while applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "In case you can’t find your UPI Handle in the dropdown list on the IPO page in the Angel One app, it means your UPI Handle is not approved by NPCI for applying for an IPO. Try to use or create an alternative UPI ID with any of the entities featured on the NPCI list."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I receive my UPI mandate request after placing an order?",
    "answer": "Below are a few things you can do: Go to your Payment App – Navigate to the mandate section and check if you have an open mandate or not. In case you have received many mandates then you can cross verify with the Application ID mentioned in the mandate details with the Application ID mentioned in the order details from Angel One’s Application OR Make sure your Payments App is updated. OR If it is taking longer than 6 hours then cancel your bid from Angel one’s application and place a new bid."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to approve an IPO mandate request?",
    "answer": "You have to approve the IPO mandate request in your UPI app."
  },
  {
    "question": "By when can I approve the UPI mandate request?",
    "answer": "Pending mandates shall expire after 5 PM on the last day. So users should accept the mandate before 5 PM on the last day to participate in the IPO."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges of applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "With Angel One, there are no charges to apply for an IPO."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can an NRI apply for an IPO using the Angel One app?",
    "answer": "NRI’s can not apply via the Angel One app. However, they can apply through the physical ASBA (Application Supported By Blocked Amount) process with your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the cut-off price & why should I apply at a cut-off price?",
    "answer": "Cut-off price is the price at which the shares get issued through an IPO to the investors. This price is ascertained at the allotment stage. When an investor applies for an IPO at a cut-off price, that means he is ready to bid at this price. In an ideal scenario, all retail investors bid at the cut-off price to increase their chance of allotment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use a bank account not linked with Angel One to apply?",
    "answer": "You can apply for an IPO using any other bank account provided the account is in the name of the investor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I apply for an IPO using my bank’s current account?",
    "answer": "It is preferred that you apply using your savings account as most banks do not process IPO applications submitted using a current account. You need to check with your bank for more details."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I apply for an IPO using my HUF’s account?",
    "answer": "You cannot apply via the Angel One app. However, you can apply using your HUF account through the physical ASBA process with your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "My daughter is a minor. Can I apply for an IPO using her account?",
    "answer": "The Angel One app doesn’t allow a minor to apply. Although, a minor can apply via physical ASBA process through your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why didn’t my account get debited after applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "As per the ASBA process, banks will simply hold/block your money when you apply for an IPO. Once the shares are allotted to you, the amount will be debited from your bank account. If the shares are not allotted to you, the amount will be unblocked/released to your account on/before the UPI mandate expiry date. Note: Banks usually take 10-15 days to release your funds. If your funds are still blocked after 15 days please contact your bank ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I modify my IPO bid?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can modify the lot size and UPI ID of your IPO bid after placing an order. Please note that if you have approved your UPI mandate request for the order and modified the order later, the entire IPO bid amount will be blocked in addition to the amount blocked for your original IPO bid. You will also receive another UPI mandate request for your modified bid. However, if you haven’t approved the original mandate request, no amount will be blocked for the original IPO bid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my IPO application rejected?",
    "answer": "Few of the common reasons your IPO application is rejected You might have entered the wrong UPI ID or UPI PIN while approving the mandate Ensuring that the Bank A/c, Demat A/c, and UPI ID are mapped to the same PAN For example: Jack is using Jill’s UPI ID to apply for an IPO with his Demat A/c. In such a case, Jack’s application will be rejected because Jill’s bank account used is not linked to the demat account of Jack Jill’s UPI ID used is not linked to Jack’s PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my funds be blocked and unblocked?",
    "answer": "Your funds will be blocked once you approve the UPI mandate request for IPO. Your funds will be unblocked/released on or before the UPI mandate expiry date if the shares are not allotted through IPO. Please reach out to your bank in case funds are not unblocked/released post the mandate expiry date."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I get a guaranteed IPO allotment?",
    "answer": "We would like to explain that Angel One is merely a platform to apply for IPO and has no control over its allotment. IPO allotment can never be guaranteed since, in case of over-subscription, the allotment is done via a lottery system. However, you can avoid application rejection by Applying from only 1 Demat account per PAN Applying at cut-off price Ensuring that the Bank A/c, Demat A/c, and UPI ID are mapped to the same PAN For example: Jack is using Jill’s UPI ID to apply for an IPO with his Demat A/c. In such a case, Jack’s application will be rejected because Jill’s bank A/C used is not linked to the Demat A/c of Jack Jill’s UPI ID used is not linked to Jack’s PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check my refund status in case of a rejected/non-allotted IPO application?",
    "answer": "Banks will simply hold/block your money when you apply for an IPO. So, your funds will be released/unblocked on or before the UPI mandate expiry date. Please reach out to your bank in case funds are not unblocked or released post the mentioned date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why didn’t I get my IPO allotment?",
    "answer": "Common reasons why you didn’t get the allotment are Non-Allotment – Allotment is done through lottery system because of over-subscription Rejection – Application can be rejected due to either of the following reasons: 1) Application received from multiple Demat accounts having the same PAN 2) Bank account Demat account, and UPI ID used for an application not mapped to the same PAN 3) Your bid price is lower than the final issue price"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is tax applicable on profit from an IPO?",
    "answer": "Tax will be levied on your profit as per your tax bracket."
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the next IPO coming?",
    "answer": "Visit our website https://www.angelone.in/upcoming-IPO to get all information about forthcoming IPO’s."
  },
  {
    "question": "I have approved the mandate request, but the status on the Angel One app is still pending. What to do?",
    "answer": "Your UPI mandate request status on the Angel One app does not get updated in real-time. It will reflect shortly in your IPO order book."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I withdraw/delete/cancel my IPO bid?",
    "answer": "For an IPO application process in the Angel One app, withdrawing, deleting, and canceling the application is the same thing. Follow the below path to withdraw/cancel your IPO application Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order you wish to cancel Tap on cancel & confirm to cancel your IPO Order"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check my IPO application status?",
    "answer": "Follow the below path to check your IPO application status Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order for which you want to check the application status Your IPO application status will be visible from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where to check the IPO allotment status?",
    "answer": "Follow the below path to check your subscription status Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order for which you want to check the subscription status Your IPO subscription status will be visible from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I submit multiple applications for an IPO?",
    "answer": "Only 1 application per PAN is recommended. Even if you apply via different platforms using the same PAN, your application will be rejected and you will not get the IPO allotment. However, you can increase the chances of IPO allotment by applying with different account linked to different PAN. For example, you can apply with your and your parents demat account separately."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I place a bid for OFS?",
    "answer": "As of now, we do not have an online facility for OFS order placement. You can Call us / Write to us by visiting the link at the bottom of the page."
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time can I bid for an Offer for Sale (OFS)?",
    "answer": "You can place your bid for OFS from 9:15 AM to 3:30 PM on the OFS date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I modify or cancel my Offer for Sale bid?",
    "answer": "Yes, cancellation and modification of orders are possible before 3:20 PM. As of now, we do not have an online facility for OFS order cancellation/modification. You can Call us / Write to us by visiting the link at the bottom of the page."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I find a list of Upcoming & past OFS?",
    "answer": "Click the link below to get the list of Upcoming & Past OFS https://www1.nseindia.com/live_market/content/live_watch/offer_sale/ofs_sale.htm"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time can I bid for an Offer for Sale (OFS)?",
    "answer": "You can place your bid for OFS from 9:15 AM to 3:30 PM on the OFS date."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many shares can I buy in an OFS?",
    "answer": "There is no specific lot size required. You can bid even for one share. However, if there is a lot size specified by the Seller as mentioned in the OFS announcement notice, orders placed in the specified lot size only will be accepted"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will the funds get debited for my OFS bid?",
    "answer": "Ledger amount will be blocked during the time of bidding. If your OFS bid has been accepted and you have been allotted shares, your account will be debited for the appropriate amount at End of Trading Day. Shares will be credited on the next T+2 days In case of oversubscription, shares will be allotted on a pro-rata basis You can also place a bid using the Margin available in your account. However, ensure you have sufficient Margin while making the bid. To find out your Margin, visit your Fund section on the Angel One app"
  },
  {
    "question": "When would the OFS shares get credited into my Demat account?",
    "answer": "If your OFS bid has been accepted and you have been allotted shares, the same will be credited to your Demat account on T + 2 days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Retail & Non-Retail category mean?",
    "answer": "Retail category is for Individual Investors with a limit of Rs 2,00,000/- for Individual bids. Non Retail category is for Organizations, FII, etc. with a bid limit greater than 2 lakhs"
  },
  {
    "question": "If allotted, how soon can I sell off my shares?",
    "answer": "Once the shares get credited into your Demat account and reflect in your Portfolio holdings, you can place your sell order any time after that."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between the Floor price and cut-off price?",
    "answer": "Floor Price is the lowest price at which you can place your bid. This price is provided by sellers. Cut off Price is the lowest price at which the OFS issue gets subscribed. This price differs for the Retail and Non Retail Categories."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I buy OFS using MTF (Margin Trading Facility)?",
    "answer": "No, it’s not possible to bid for OFS using MTF."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I place multiple bids for Offer for Sale?",
    "answer": "Yes you can place multiple bids for Offer for Sale. Further, investors opting for multiple orders across Exchanges should be aware that all bids in the Retail category amounting to more than Rs 2,00,000 will be rejected."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many watchlists can be added?",
    "answer": "You can add up to 5 watchlists."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many stocks can be added in each watchlist?",
    "answer": "You can add up to 50 stocks per watchlist."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I create a watchlist?",
    "answer": "You can create a watchlist by following these steps. Go to watchlist screen. On web as well as mobile app, you will find a + icon to create a new watchlist. Name the watchlist and click on create. You can search the stocks and add them to the created watchlists."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are recommendations?",
    "answer": "Recommendations are stocks suggested by Angel One to help you minimize risk and maximize profit. You can see the recommendations by visiting https://www.angelone.in/trade/home You will find the recommendations under “Top Stock Picks via Advisory” section on this screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges for recommendations?",
    "answer": "We don’t charge any fee for recommendations. The usual trading charges will be levied when a user takes a trade."
  },
  {
    "question": "Recommend me some best growing stocks?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can also explore the Portfolio advisory on the home screen if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Suggest me some stocks for short term or intraday?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can explore the Portfolio advisory if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Suggest me stocks for long term investment?",
    "answer": "Angel One provides you recommendations through advisory services. Based on extensive research, we provide portfolio and single stock advisory. To explore the more you can check Single stock advisory on the home screen of Angel One web or mobile platform. Here you will find suggestions for Intraday, Short and Long term stocks. You can explore the Portfolio advisory if you want to buy a group of stocks."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is MPIN?",
    "answer": "An MPIN is a 4-digit PIN used for two-factor authentication, enhancing your account security. It is used for logging into your Angel One account."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I enable MPIN?",
    "answer": "Go to Account → Settings → Change/Enable MPIN . Enter the old MPIN and confirm the new MPIN. Click on Submit. This will enable a new MPIN for your account. Please keep your MPIN confidential."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I enable fingerprint login for my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "Go to Account → Settings → Fingerprint. Confirm your fingerprint. This will enable fingerprint for your login. Note: This feature is only available for Android devices. For iOS, use Face ID detection."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change my PIN on the Angel One mobile app?",
    "answer": "Go to Account → Settings → Change/Enable MPIN . Enter the old MPIN and confirm the new MPIN. Click on Submit. This will enable a new MPIN for your account. Please keep your MPIN confidential."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change MPIN on the web?",
    "answer": "Logout of the web platform. Enter your mobile number or client code. Enter the OTP received on your email and mobile. Click on “Forgot PIN.” Verify the OTP and set a new PIN."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many watchlists can be added?",
    "answer": "You can add up to 5 watchlists."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many stocks can be added in each watchlist?",
    "answer": "You can add up to 50 stocks per watchlist."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I create a watchlist?",
    "answer": "You can create a watchlist by following these steps. Go to watchlist screen. On web as well as mobile app, you will find a + icon to create a new watchlist. Name the watchlist and click on create. You can search the stocks and add them to the created watchlists."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to apply for a Rights Issue?",
    "answer": "Investors can apply for Right Issue shares only through the Application Supported by Blocked Amount i.e. ASBA, either online or offline, if they hold Right Entitlement in their demat account. Online ASBA Process: Most Self-Certified Syndicate Banks (SCSBs) support the online ASBA application process through Net Banking, similar to an IPO application. Investors should refer to their respective SCSB’s website for detailed instructions on applying for the Rights Issue. Offline ASBA Process: Alternatively, investors can apply by submitting a filled application form at the nearest branch of an SCSB (Self Certified Syndicate Bank). The list of eligible branches is available on the SEBI website . The Composite Application form (CAF) can be downloaded from NSE, BSE and RTA websites. Investors can also view and download the Rights Issue Application Form (CAF) , Offer Letter, Abridged Letter & Entitlement Ratio – Applicable only for registered holders with holdings as of Record Date, from the RTA website. RTA don’t directly accept Right Issue application forms (online/offline). Application needs to be channeled through SCSBs only."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to obtain the Right Entitlement (RE) ?",
    "answer": "Directly from RTA if the investor is eligible for the Right Issue by holding shares of the Company on the record date . Purchasing from the Market – Investors can buy Right Entitlement (RE) from the secondary market through the trading platforms such as Angel One, generally identifiable with “-RE” at the end of the stock symbol. Important Note: Holding or purchasing Right Entitlement (RE) does not automatically grant ownership of the Rights Issue shares. Investors must apply for the Rights Issue using their RE before the application deadline. Failure to do so will result in the renouncement of rights, leading to a loss of value. The RTA website is only for viewing the Rights Issue Application Form, Offer Letter, Abridged Letter & Entitlement Ratio – Applicable only for registered holders with holdings as of Record Date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are my shares in Pool Account?",
    "answer": "Shares will be in pool account due to 2 reasons: Your account is in debit Shares have not been settled yet. Shares are settled on Trading day + 2 days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are my shares that I sold from my Portfolio shown as negative in Positions tab?",
    "answer": "Positions tab shows all the positions taken by you today. A negative quantity indicates a sell transaction whereas a positive quantity indicates a buy transaction."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my shares be credited to my demat account?",
    "answer": "Your shares will be credited to your demat account on either T+1 or T+2 trading days depending upon the settlement cycle of the share where T is the trading day."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are realized and unrealized gains?",
    "answer": "An unrealized gain/loss is the increase/decrease in the value of an asset or investment that an investor holds but has not yet sold for cash. It is called unrealized; gain/loss because the investor hasn’t booked the profit/loss until he actually sells that investment. A gain or loss becomes realized when the investment is actually sold."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I check my Portfolio/Holdings?",
    "answer": "Tap on Portfolio at the bottom of your screen You will be able to see your Holdings/Portfolio from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "I bought my shares on BSE. Why are they shown on NSE in my Portfolio?",
    "answer": "We are doing all our settlements in NSE as per our internal policy. Follow the below path to sell shares in BSE Click on the share you wish to sell from your Portfolio & tap on Sell Click on 3 dots on the top right hand corner & change the Exchange from NSE to BSE or vice versa. Your share will now be sold on BSE"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my portfolio be updated with my latest investments?",
    "answer": "Your Portfolio will be updated with your latest investments on an immediate basis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I find the average price changed for some stocks in my portfolio?",
    "answer": "3 things that affect the average price change for certain stocks are: FIFO (First In, First Out) method is used while calculating the average price Changes in corporate action handling for certain stocks Changes in decimal digits while calculating the average price. Here are all the details about the average price change you would want to know."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are DP Charges?",
    "answer": "DP(Depository Participant) charges are applied at the time of selling shares from your DEMAT account. DP Charges are levied on a per-scrip, per-transaction basis. They don’t depend on the quantity of shares you sold, but on the number of different scrips/shares/securities that you sell. DP Charges are levied at Rs 20 (+ 18% GST) per scrip per transaction."
  },
  {
    "question": "When are DP Charges levied?",
    "answer": "DP Charges are levied whenever you sell equity delivery shares from your Angel One account. They are not applicable to equity buy, intraday, or F&O transactions. DP Charges are levied on a per-scrip basis and do not depend on the quantity or the units sold."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Account Maintenance Charge (AMC) at Angel One?",
    "answer": "Account Maintenance Charge (AMC) is a fixed quarterly charge that is billed to your account. Account maintenance charges for the first year are 0. However, the following are the charges for customers from 2nd year onwards. Non-BSDA (Basic Services Demat Account) Clients – Rs. 60+ GST billed every quarter (Charged after your first trade each quarter). For BSDA Clients – If the holding value is less than 4 lakh, AMC is 0. If the holding value is between 4 lakh and 10 lakh, AMC is Rs. 100+GST billed every year. You can check the AMC levied to your account by navigating to Account → Trades and Charges → Other Charges screen on the app."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check the Account Maintenance Charges levied to my account?",
    "answer": "You can easily check the AMC charges levied to your account in the Angel One app. Please visit Account → Trades and Charges → Other Charges screen and select the desired data range to check the AMC charges."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much is the account maintenance charge on Angel One?",
    "answer": "Account maintenance charges for the first year are 0. However, the following are the charges for customers from 2nd year onwards. Non-BSDA (Basic Services Demat Account) Clients – Rs. 60+ GST billed every quarter (Charged after your first trade each quarter). For BSDA Clients – If the holding value is less than 4 lakh, AMC is 0. If the holding value is between 4 lakh and 10 lakh, AMC is Rs. 100+GST billed every year. You can check the AMC levied to your account by navigating to Account → Trades and Charges → Other Charges screen on the app."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are BSDA and non-BSDA accounts?",
    "answer": "BSDA (Basic Services Demat Account) BSDA accounts provide limited services at a lower cost to retail account holders. Your account will be automatically a BSDA if it fulfills both the below conditions. You have only 1 Demat account across all stock brokers. The value of holdings in your account is less than 10 lakh. Non-BSDA Accounts that do not fulfill the above-mentioned criteria of BSDA are categorized as Non-BSDA."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check my BSDA status?",
    "answer": "You can check your BSDA status in client master list (CML). However, we don’t have a facility to download the CML from our platform. We are working on making it available to you soon."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change my mobile number registered with Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can directly submit mobile number modification request online via the Angel One app. Please click here or follow the below steps to submit a request. Navigate to the Profile section on the Account screen of the app. Click on Personal Details . Click on the pen icon next to your mobile number. Here you will be able to submit a modification request by adding your new mobile number. Please note that you need to verify the OTP and Esign to submit the request. Once the request is submitted successfully, your mobile number will be updated within 3-5 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I add new bank account details on Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can directly submit bank account addition requests online via the Angel One app. Please click here or follow the steps below to submit a request. Navigate to the Profile section on the Account screen of the app. Click on Bank Accounts. You can add a new bank account by adding the Account Number and IFSC Code. Please note that you will receive an option to set up the new account as the primary account during the process. Once you submit the request, bank details will be approved in 2-3 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I modify existing bank account details on Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can submit a bank account modification request online via the Angel One App. Please click here or follow the steps below to submit a request. Navigate to the Profile Section on the Account Screen of the app. Click on Bank Accounts. Click on the three dots next to the bank account you wish to modify. Enter the new IFSC code and submit the request. Please note that you can change the IFSC code and set the bank account as primary while modifying the details. Add a new bank account if you wish to use a different bank on the Angel One app. Once you submit the request, bank details will be approved in 2-3 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I remove or delete a bank account on Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can now delete a bank account from your Trading Account via our website or app. Follow the steps below to delete a bank account through the Angel One App. Step 1: Log in to the Angel One App Step 2: Go to ‘Account’ >> click on ‘Profile Name’> Step 3: Click on ‘Bank Account’ Step 4: Now, click on the 3 dots against the bank account you wish to delete Step 5: Click ‘Delete’ and reconfirm deletion by clicking ‘Yes, Delete’ Step 6: Continue to E-Sign Step 7: Submit the OTP sent to your registered mobile number to authenticate the transaction Please note the following points before deleting a bank account on Angel One. You can add up to 5 bank accounts with Angel One. Even if a bank account is not being used anymore, you can add a new bank account or use any other existing bank account for all transaction-related purposes. Once you submit the request, bank details will be approved in 2-3 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I set a bank account as primary?",
    "answer": "Follow the steps below to set up a bank account as a primary account through the Angel One App. Step 1: Log in to the Angel One App Step 2: Go to ‘Account’ >> click on ‘Profile Name’> Step 3: Click on ‘Bank Account’ Step 4: Now, click on the 3 dots against the bank account you wish to delete Step 5: Click ‘Set as Primary’ Step 6: Continue to E-Sign Step 7: Submit the OTP sent to your registered mobile number to authenticate the transaction Once you submit the request, bank details will be approved in 2-3 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate DDPI online?",
    "answer": "You can activate DDPI online by following the below steps on the Angel One app by clicking here . Navigate to the Account → Profile → DDPI Status section on Angel One. Enter your Aadhaar number and verify the OTP received on the mobile number linked with the Aadhaar. After successful verification, processing will be done in 2-4 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate POA online?",
    "answer": "The POA process is now replaced with DDPI. You can activate DDPI online by following the below steps on the Angel One app. Navigate to the Account → Profile → DDPI Status section on Angel One. Enter your Aadhaar number and verify the OTP received on the mobile number linked with the Aadhaar. After successful verification, processing will be done in 2-4 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the benefits of activating DDPI?",
    "answer": "Activating DDPI (Demat Debit and Pledge Instructions) for your account provides several benefits: You do not have to verify TPIN while selling stocks. You can place sell GTT (Good Till Triggered) orders. DDPI should be activated to participate in the buyback process."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I add/modify the nominee details on Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can add or modify nominee details online via the Angel One app by clicking here . Please follow the steps below to submit a request. Navigate to Account → Profile → Nominee section of the app. Click on Add Nominee. You will need to enter the Name, DoB, Valid ID proof, Relationship, % share to be allocated, and address for each nominee. The total share percentage should be 100%. Once you submit the request, the details will be updated in 3 working days. In case, the nominee is a minor, you will need to provide the nominee’s guardian details. Guardian cannot be a minor. Enter your Aadhaar number and verify the OTP received on the mobile number linked with the Aadhaar to submit the request."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I change my email ID registered with Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can directly submit Email ID modification requests online via the Angel One app. Please click here or follow the below steps to submit a request. Navigate to the Profile section on the Account screen of the app. Click on Personal Details . Click on the pen icon next to your Email ID. Here you will be able to submit a modification request by adding your new Email ID. Please note that you need to verify the OTP and Esign to submit the request. Once the request is submitted successfully, your Email ID will be updated within 3-5 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I modify my address/location registered with Angel One?",
    "answer": "You can modify the address details online via the Angel One app by clicking here . Please follow the steps below to submit a request. Navigate to Account → Profile → Personal Details section of the app. Click on the pen icon next to your location. You will be navigated to the Digilocker page to enter the Aadhar details. Provide the Aadhar number and verify the OTP. Please note that the address should be first updated in your Aadhar records. Angel One automatically fetches the address details from your Aadhar. Once you submit the request, the details will be updated in 5 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my BO ID?",
    "answer": "You can find your BO ID on the Profile page of the app. Alternatively, you can navigate to Account → Profile → Demat Account Details . Your 16-digit BO ID is mentioned here. It is also called the Demat Account Number. Please note that the BO ID is required for TPIN verification and IPO application in case your DDPI is not active."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is DP ID and where can I find it?",
    "answer": "DP ID stands for Depository Participant Identification. It is a unique identification number assigned to a Depository Participant (DP) such as Angel One. You can find your DP ID on the Profile page of the app. Alternatively, you can navigate to Account → Profile → Demat Account Details . Your 8-digit DP ID is mentioned here."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my client code?",
    "answer": "Your client code is a unique identifier for your account with Angel One. You can find your client ID on the Profile page of the app."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my demat account number?",
    "answer": "You can find your Demat Account Number on the Profile page of the app. It is also called BO ID."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I find the profile section on the Angel One app?",
    "answer": "If you are using the web platform, you will find the profile section in the “Account” screen. If you are using the mobile app, you will find the profile section at the top right corner of the “Account” screen or under the “Trading Balance” section."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the NAV for my order?",
    "answer": "Applicable NAV is based on realization of fund by respective AMC house and subject to successful order processing by BSE star before cut-offs. Here ‘realization of funds’ means that NAV applicable for your order will depend on if the fund house has receievd money or not Please find the cut-off timings for various types of funds and orders Furthermore, NAV applicability for orders placed on Saturday, Sundays and other market/public holidays depends on when orders are placed on exchange. Here it is the next business day. Payments made via UPI mode generally result in same-day NAV if the order is placed before cut-off. This happens because settlement to ICCL happens generally happens before cut-off if made via UPI. Angel One depends on payment aggregator for ICCL settlements. Payments made via Netbanking generally result in next working day’s NAV. This happens as settlement to ICCL does not happen real time and generally takes places on ‘T+1’ basis. Angel One depends on payment aggregator for ICCL settlements. So even if order and payment is successful before cut-off, If the payment mode is netbanking, This might result in next day’s NAV. In Summary, In some cases, Even if order and payment happens before cut-off, NAV will depend on settlement to ICCL and realization of funds by AMC"
  },
  {
    "question": "I am not able to view my SIP order that I placed recently?",
    "answer": "Your orders will appear in orders only if you have made the payment today. If you have not selected ‘Make first payment now’. Your SIPs will appear only in SIPS section To view all your registered SIPs click please go to SIPs section or click on the link below: Manage SIPs"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my investment appear in my portfolio?",
    "answer": "Your Investments will appear in your ‘investments Tab’ when your orders moves to ‘Completed’ section of your Orders Tab. This happens when we get th e confirmation of Unit allotment by respective AMCs. This process generally takes 3/4 working days from order placement date. Your portfolio updation date in Order timeline is our estimate of when Unit allotment confirmation from AMC will come through. Please do not worry, This date date does not have any relation to your NAV date. Your NAV date depend on realization of funds by AMC."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my instalment order in progress if SIP date is yet to come?",
    "answer": "We generally create your SIP installment order 2/3 working days before your due date as we have to co-ordinate with your Auto-pay linked bank account well in advance to ensure your SIP instalments goes through smoothly on due date. Order Date is when we create your SIP instalment order in our system and SIP due date is when money will be debited from your Autopay linked bank account. NAV applicable is usually of your SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will SIP amount get debited from my bank account for my Active SIPs?",
    "answer": "Your money will get debited automatically only if your SIP is linked to an autopay. If your SIP is linked to an autopay. SIP amount will get debited on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my order get successful?",
    "answer": "We have not received confirmation of successful payment from your bank. We will update the status as soon as possible. Your order will be confirmed when we receive confirmation of payment and confirmation of order placement by exchange. If both this stages are completed successfully. Your order will be successful. Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "What will happen if I do not have sufficient balance in my bank account on SIP due date?",
    "answer": "Your SIP instalment will fail if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your autopay linked bank account. Your bank can also charge you if you do not ensure sufficient balance in your bank account on SIP due date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Money got deducted from my bank account but payment status shows payment in progress?",
    "answer": "We have not received confirmation of successful payment from your bank account. We will update the status as soon as possible. Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will refund happen if money has been debited but order has failed?",
    "answer": "Please don’t worry, If we do not get confirmation or if payment fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "My money got debited but transaction shows as failed. When will refund happen?",
    "answer": "Please don’t worry, If we do not get payment confirmation or if payment/ order fails. Entire amount will be debited to your source bank account in 4-6 working days."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my SIP get created if my order is in Failed state?",
    "answer": "No, Your SIP will only be created when we received confirmation of successful payment from your bank account. If payment fails, Your SIP payment will not be registered."
  },
  {
    "question": "I got less money than what I placed an withdrawal order for?",
    "answer": "Your withdraw amount is converted to corresponding units while placing order at exchange. We calculate the units to be withdrawn based on current NAVs. Mutual fund NAVs (Net Asset Value) are updated every day after the market closes from Monday to Friday (All working days) For example, on June 3rd, you will see the NAV for June 2nd. Consider the following scenario for withdraw order placed on June 3rd: If NAV on 3rd June > 2nd June, You will receive an amount greater than order amount. If NAV on 3rd June < 2nd June, You will receive an amount lesser than order amount. In Summary, you will receive an amount according to latest NAV."
  },
  {
    "question": "Will my next instalment be auto-debited?",
    "answer": "Your next SIP instalment will be Auto-Debited from your bank account if you have a valid Auto-pay setup. If not please setup an Autopay so that your future SIP instalments can be automated. To setup an Autopay, Please click below: {Setup Autopay}"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Stamp duty?",
    "answer": "The government collects 0.005% of the overall purchase amount of any mutual fund scheme as stamp duty. So even if entire amount is debited from your bank account, 0.005 percent of total amount is deducted and hence when order is completed, Same is reflected as invested amount."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I find my UPI ID?",
    "answer": "Generally, you can find your UPI ID in the profile section of the respective app you are using."
  },
  {
    "question": "I don’t have a UPI ID. Can I apply for an IPO?",
    "answer": "In case you don’t have a UPI ID, you can create it with any of the UPI Handles featured in the NPCI list. Alternatively, you can apply through ASBA with your bank or through physical form."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I create my UPI ID?",
    "answer": "You can follow the below steps to create a UPI ID with the BHIM app Download the Google Pay/ PhonePe / BHIM App Verify your mobile number Register the passcode (it is required to open the app) Select your bank from the options available The app will fetch your bank details In case you have more than one account, choose the account you want to register with BHIM Set up a UPI PIN for security Now you can check your UPI ID in the profile section."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to apply for IPOs via my UPI ID/Handle?",
    "answer": "For IPO applications, only UPI ID/Handles approved by NPCI are allowed. In case you are unable to apply for IPO using your UPI ID/Handle, we recommend that you check the list of banks/apps approved by NPCI for providing UPI service for IPO application."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can’t I see my UPI handle listed in the dropdown in the Angel One app while applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "In case you can’t find your UPI Handle in the dropdown list on the IPO page in the Angel One app, it means your UPI Handle is not approved by NPCI for applying for an IPO. Try to use or create an alternative UPI ID with any of the entities featured on the NPCI list."
  },
  {
    "question": "When will I receive my UPI mandate request after placing an order?",
    "answer": "Below are a few things you can do: Go to your Payment App – Navigate to the mandate section and check if you have an open mandate or not. In case you have received many mandates then you can cross verify with the Application ID mentioned in the mandate details with the Application ID mentioned in the order details from Angel One’s Application OR Make sure your Payments App is updated. OR If it is taking longer than 6 hours then cancel your bid from Angel one’s application and place a new bid."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to approve an IPO mandate request?",
    "answer": "You have to approve the IPO mandate request in your UPI app."
  },
  {
    "question": "By when can I approve the UPI mandate request?",
    "answer": "Pending mandates shall expire after 5 PM on the last day. So users should accept the mandate before 5 PM on the last day to participate in the IPO."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the charges of applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "With Angel One, there are no charges to apply for an IPO."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can an NRI apply for an IPO using the Angel One app?",
    "answer": "NRI’s can not apply via the Angel One app. However, they can apply through the physical ASBA (Application Supported By Blocked Amount) process with your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the cut-off price & why should I apply at a cut-off price?",
    "answer": "Cut-off price is the price at which the shares get issued through an IPO to the investors. This price is ascertained at the allotment stage. When an investor applies for an IPO at a cut-off price, that means he is ready to bid at this price. In an ideal scenario, all retail investors bid at the cut-off price to increase their chance of allotment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I use a bank account not linked with Angel One to apply?",
    "answer": "You can apply for an IPO using any other bank account provided the account is in the name of the investor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I apply for an IPO using my bank’s current account?",
    "answer": "It is preferred that you apply using your savings account as most banks do not process IPO applications submitted using a current account. You need to check with your bank for more details."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I apply for an IPO using my HUF’s account?",
    "answer": "You cannot apply via the Angel One app. However, you can apply using your HUF account through the physical ASBA process with your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "My daughter is a minor. Can I apply for an IPO using her account?",
    "answer": "The Angel One app doesn’t allow a minor to apply. Although, a minor can apply via physical ASBA process through your bank."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why didn’t my account get debited after applying for an IPO?",
    "answer": "As per the ASBA process, banks will simply hold/block your money when you apply for an IPO. Once the shares are allotted to you, the amount will be debited from your bank account. If the shares are not allotted to you, the amount will be unblocked/released to your account on/before the UPI mandate expiry date. Note: Banks usually take 10-15 days to release your funds. If your funds are still blocked after 15 days please contact your bank ."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I modify my IPO bid?",
    "answer": "Yes, you can modify the lot size and UPI ID of your IPO bid after placing an order. Please note that if you have approved your UPI mandate request for the order and modified the order later, the entire IPO bid amount will be blocked in addition to the amount blocked for your original IPO bid. You will also receive another UPI mandate request for your modified bid. However, if you haven’t approved the original mandate request, no amount will be blocked for the original IPO bid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is my IPO application rejected?",
    "answer": "Few of the common reasons your IPO application is rejected You might have entered the wrong UPI ID or UPI PIN while approving the mandate Ensuring that the Bank A/c, Demat A/c, and UPI ID are mapped to the same PAN For example: Jack is using Jill’s UPI ID to apply for an IPO with his Demat A/c. In such a case, Jack’s application will be rejected because Jill’s bank account used is not linked to the demat account of Jack Jill’s UPI ID used is not linked to Jack’s PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "When will my funds be blocked and unblocked?",
    "answer": "Your funds will be blocked once you approve the UPI mandate request for IPO. Your funds will be unblocked/released on or before the UPI mandate expiry date if the shares are not allotted through IPO. Please reach out to your bank in case funds are not unblocked/released post the mandate expiry date."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I get a guaranteed IPO allotment?",
    "answer": "We would like to explain that Angel One is merely a platform to apply for IPO and has no control over its allotment. IPO allotment can never be guaranteed since, in case of over-subscription, the allotment is done via a lottery system. However, you can avoid application rejection by Applying from only 1 Demat account per PAN Applying at cut-off price Ensuring that the Bank A/c, Demat A/c, and UPI ID are mapped to the same PAN For example: Jack is using Jill’s UPI ID to apply for an IPO with his Demat A/c. In such a case, Jack’s application will be rejected because Jill’s bank A/C used is not linked to the Demat A/c of Jack Jill’s UPI ID used is not linked to Jack’s PAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I check my refund status in case of a rejected/non-allotted IPO application?",
    "answer": "Banks will simply hold/block your money when you apply for an IPO. So, your funds will be released/unblocked on or before the UPI mandate expiry date. Please reach out to your bank in case funds are not unblocked or released post the mentioned date."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why didn’t I get my IPO allotment?",
    "answer": "Common reasons why you didn’t get the allotment are Non-Allotment – Allotment is done through lottery system because of over-subscription Rejection – Application can be rejected due to either of the following reasons: 1) Application received from multiple Demat accounts having the same PAN 2) Bank account Demat account, and UPI ID used for an application not mapped to the same PAN 3) Your bid price is lower than the final issue price"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is tax applicable on profit from an IPO?",
    "answer": "Tax will be levied on your profit as per your tax bracket."
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the next IPO coming?",
    "answer": "Visit our website https://www.angelone.in/upcoming-IPO to get all information about forthcoming IPO’s."
  },
  {
    "question": "I have approved the mandate request, but the status on the Angel One app is still pending. What to do?",
    "answer": "Your UPI mandate request status on the Angel One app does not get updated in real-time. It will reflect shortly in your IPO order book."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I withdraw/delete/cancel my IPO bid?",
    "answer": "For an IPO application process in the Angel One app, withdrawing, deleting, and canceling the application is the same thing. Follow the below path to withdraw/cancel your IPO application Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order you wish to cancel Tap on cancel & confirm to cancel your IPO Order"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check my IPO application status?",
    "answer": "Follow the below path to check your IPO application status Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order for which you want to check the application status Your IPO application status will be visible from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where to check the IPO allotment status?",
    "answer": "Follow the below path to check your subscription status Tap on IPO on the Home page Click on IPO orders & click on the IPO Order for which you want to check the subscription status Your IPO subscription status will be visible from here"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I submit multiple applications for an IPO?",
    "answer": "Only 1 application per PAN is recommended. Even if you apply via different platforms using the same PAN, your application will be rejected and you will not get the IPO allotment. However, you can increase the chances of IPO allotment by applying with different account linked to different PAN. For example, you can apply with your and your parents demat account separately."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is family declaration?",
    "answer": "As per regulatory requirement, every KYC account should have a separate and unique mobile number and email address . In case if account holder wishes to use common email Id/ Mobile number for more than one account of family, it can be done after submitting a written declaration giving required details and duly signed by people involved."
  },
  {
    "question": "What relationships are permitted as per SEBI to be considered as family for this purpose?",
    "answer": "Family for this purpose has been defined by SEBI as self, spouse, dependent parents and dependent children (in case of individual account holders)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What relationship can be given for clients having no- individual category of account such as company, trust, HUF, AOP etc.",
    "answer": "In case of non-individual category of account, if common email id/mobile number is used for more than one account then relationship can be defined as “Authorised Signatory” and the supporting needs to be submitted along with declaration such as Board resolution copy, trust/partnership deed or other such officially valid document approved giving detalils of authorized persons."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are siblings or other relationships such as daughter-in-law, son-in-law allowed for considering family for this purpose?",
    "answer": "No. Only SEBI defined relationships of self, spouse, dependent parents and dependent children are allowed to be considered as family for this purpose. Anything else apart from this is not allowed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What if the client is found to be using the common email id/mobile number without allowable relationship?",
    "answer": "Such account will be considered as invalid KYC accounts and will be suspended in both trading and demat account till the time unique valid KYC credentials are updated."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the client change their email ID and/or Mobile number to avoid non-compliance?",
    "answer": "Modification request can be submitted to change the mobile number/email ID by submitting request from the profile page of client’s account login."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can a client find the Family Declaration Form?",
    "answer": "Client can download the Family Declaration Form from here . Send the duly signed scan copy on support@angelbroking.com .  Hard copy of declaration can be sent at below mentioned address. Angel One Limited. 5th Floor Akruti Star Andheri (E) Mumbai- 400 093"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who needs to sign the Family Declaration Form?",
    "answer": "The client who wants to use common email Id/ Mobile number, will mention the demat and trading account details and sign at the bottom of the page. If the demat account has more than one holder, all the holders will sign at respective place. The person who is Sellf (whose email id /mobile number is used will sign at the place “Signature of the related person”."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Stamp Duty charges?",
    "answer": "Stamp duty is a direct tax levied on trading in stocks, currency derivatives and commodities, payable under Section 3 of the Indian Stamp Act, 1899."
  },
  {
    "question": "Are indicators and drawings on charts free or paid?",
    "answer": "All the indicators are absolutely free on the Angel One."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are my drawings not getting retained on charts?",
    "answer": "All Drawings under templates are stored inside the local storage. If you login through other devices you won’t be able to view previously saved drawings on other device/browser."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where to find Drawing tools on charts?",
    "answer": "On Web or on Mobile platforms, click on blue arrow button that is present on left side of the charts – by clicking on it, it will give an expanded view of the drawing tools available"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I set price or volume alerts on the Angel One mobile app?",
    "answer": "You can set a price or volume alert on the Angel One mobile app by following the below steps. Select the desired stock and click on Stock details. Click on the alarm icon in the top right corner. Set alerts based on either price or volume; Configure the parameters & conditions. Press Create Alert. To view or modify alerts, go to the home page, click the bell icon at the top, and visit the Alerts section."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I set price or volume alerts on the web?",
    "answer": "Hover over the desired stock in your watchlist. Go to the overflow menu (⋮). Click Add Alert. Choose between Price Action and Technical Indicators. Configure the parameters, conditions, and other details. Press Create Alert. To view or modify alerts, go to the Orders tab and visit the Alerts section."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I enable or disable notifications?",
    "answer": "Notifications can be managed only on the mobile app. To change notification settings: Go to Account. Select Settings. Scroll to Manage Notification at the bottom of the screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can I see my account balance?",
    "answer": "Tap on Account at the bottom of your screen Trading balance is shown at on the card at the top of the page Click on Trading balance card to view more details about the funds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is my Available Margin to Trade?",
    "answer": "Available Margin to Trade consists of your Funds balance & margin against eligible holdings."
  },
  {
    "question": "How to increase my Available Margin to Trade?",
    "answer": "You can increase your Available Margin to Trade by adding Funds or by creating a Margin Pledge against your eligible holdings in Accounts -> Stock Pledging."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Peak Margin requirement?",
    "answer": "Peak Margin is the minimum margin that must be collected by brokers from their clients in advance of placing any intraday / delivery order."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Peak Margin Shortfall?",
    "answer": "Peak Margin shortfall occurs when you buy a share from 80% margin released against delivery sell transactions and such sell position is subsequently bought back. You will be charged a penalty if margin shortfall is due to insufficient margin."
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to know how much cash is mine and how much is on margin?",
    "answer": "You can check your available cash and margin by visiting Account → Trading balance screen on web or mobile app. Here you will see the Cash balance and the margins from pledge holdings"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate the Futures & Options (F&O) segment for my account?",
    "answer": "You can activate the F&O segment online via the Angel One app. You can request for segment activation by clicking here . But before that, please go through the below steps. Navigate to Account → Profile → Manage Segment section of the app. Select the segments to be activated. If you don’t have equity holdings in your account, providing financial proof is mandatory. You can automatically provide a 6-month bank statement as financial proof by entering the bank name and mobile number linked to your bank. You can also manually upload the 6 months bank statement as financial proof. If you don’t have bank statement, you can provide any of the below documents as financial proof. Passbook Salary Slip ITR Acknowledgement Form 16 Demat Account Statement You will be redirected for e-signing the request. Enter the Aadhar details & OTP sent from Adhaar on your mobile number. The request will be processed in 2 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why am I unable to trade in F&O even though the segment is activated?",
    "answer": "If you have recently activated your F&O segment, kindly wait for 1 working day from the date of activation. You will be able to start trading after 1 working day."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate the commodity or MCX segment for my account?",
    "answer": "You can activate the commodity or MCX segment online via the Angel One app. You can request for segment activation by clicking here . But before that, please go through the below steps. Navigate to Account → Profile → Manage Segment section of the app. Select the segments to be activated. If you don’t have equity holdings in your account, providing financial proof is mandatory. You can automatically provide 6-month bank statement as financial proof by entering the bank name and mobile number linked to your bank. You can also manually upload the 6 months bank statement as financial proof. If you don’t have bank statement, you can provide any of the below documents as financial proof. Passbook Salary Slip ITR Acknowledgement Form 16 Demat Account Statement You will be redirected for e-signing the request. Enter the Aadhar details & OTP sent from Adhaar on your mobile number. The request will be processed in 3 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I activate the currency segment for my account?",
    "answer": "You can activate the currency segment online via the Angel One app. You can request for segment activation by clicking here . But before that, please go through the below steps. Navigate to Account → Profile → Manage Segment section of the app. Select the segments to be activated. If you don’t have equity holdings in your account, providing financial proof is mandatory. You can automatically provide 6-month bank statement as financial proof by entering the bank name and mobile number linked to your bank. You can also manually upload the 6 months bank statement as financial proof. If you don’t have bank statement, you can provide any of the below documents as financial proof. Passbook Salary Slip ITR Acknowledgement Form 16 Demat Account Statement You will be redirected for e-signing the request. Enter the Aadhar details & OTP sent from Adhaar on your mobile number. The request will be processed in 3 working days. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I check the segment activation status in my Angel One account?",
    "answer": "When you open an account with Angel One, Equit, and Mutual Fund segments are automatically activated. You need to submit an activation request if you want to trade in F&O, Commodity, or Currency segments. You can check your segment activation status by clicking here . Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I need to activate the F&O, Commodity, and Currency segments?",
    "answer": "Your equity trading and Mutual fund segments are already activated once your Angel One is opened. However, your Derivatives Trading (i.e. F&O, Commodity, and Currency trading) is considered a separate segment that has to be activated separately from the profile section. Please visit this page for a more detailed guide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I deactivate a segment?",
    "answer": "We currently do not have an online option to deactivate segments. However, you can raise a ticket if you wish to deactivate any segment."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why doesn't my Limit order get executed after I reach the price I want?",
    "answer": "It does not guarantee that your order will be executed even if your price has been reached. Orders are queued while being bought or sold. For Example. Assume you placed a Buy limit order of 100 Rs for the ABC script. Let’s say there are 100 buyers and 50 sellers waiting to trade in ABC at 100. ABC is currently trading at 105 Rs and after a few minutes, it reaches 100 Rs. Since there are only 50 sellers for 100 Rs, only 50 buyers will be able to buy the script once this price is reached. As for the other 50 buyers, they’ll have to wait until more sellers become available."
  }
]